<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-09-04</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1' facs="/sites/default/files/2025-08/0001_1942-09-30_001_0.jpg"/>
					<dateline>F-10-4 FANC.
					Sept. 30, 1942</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother, Dad + Grandma--</salute>
					<p>First of all, I'll get business out of the
					way, and then later I can tell you the news.
					I mailed a package to you this evening. I'm
					sending back some of the stockings you sent,
					mother; I can't use anything but known or tan
					socks. I'm also sending the letters I have received
					so far. Store them somewhere for me -- I want to
					save them. Also one of the books you sent for
					which I have no use, and the B.U. Handbook
					which I have read and want to save. Put it
					with the previous hand books -- in the bookcase,
					I think. I'm also including the battery picture.
					My barracks is on the top row all the way
					across. The battery officers are on the ground.
					Jerry Roche, the Wilkes Barre boy, I've been
					paling with is third from the left top. I think
					you'll have no trouble finding me.</p>
				<p>
					Also, I'm sending a sort of booklet on
					Fort Bragg. It may be the same one Hen 
					Wolfe showed you. Anyway when you've
					finished looking at it, file it away for me.

				<pb n='2' facs="/sites/default/files/2025-08/0002_1942-09-30_002.jpg"/>

					It will be nice to show to my grandchildren.
				</p>
				<p>
					Enclosed in this letter, you'll find a
					money order for $20. Please deposit that amount
					to my checking account.
				</p>
				<p>
					As you can guess from the above paragraph,
					today was payday. I drew $30.71. I still
					had the $10 partial pay we received before, so I
					have all the cash I shall need til next payday.
					The $6.60 monthly insurance payment was deducted
					before I even saw the pay envelope, as was the
					charge for laundry, picture, etc.
				</p>
				<p>
					I have signed up to have an $18.75 bond
					deducted from my pay in the future. With
					insurance deduction, etc., I will thus get
					approximately $22 a month cash in the
					future. The bond will be sent home to you,
					Dad, beginning next month. Please put
					them in the bank box with my other bonds as
					they come. I had Dad's name put on as
					co-owner. O.K.?
				</p>
				<p>
					Now for the news. We are beginning to
					learn a bit about artillery, and, of course
					more about telephone, etc. We have been
					warned repeatedly about disclosing military
					information, so I guess in the future I won't

				<pb n='3' facs="/sites/default/files/2025-08/0003_1942-09-30_003_0.jpg"/>
				
				be able to tell you the actual details of my
				technical training.</p>
				<p>My physical condition is much
					improved; I'm sure, but I haven't been
					weighed, so I don't know whether I've
					lost appreciably or not. Boxing class is
					getting more and more strenuous, and
					I'm able to take it without more serious
					after effects than loss of breath. Yesterday
					we ran the quarter mile -- and I passed
					quite a few of the younger boys who should
					be in fairly good condition.</p>
				<p>Both Monday and today we went
					over an obstacle course. It's really tough.
					Just like a steeple chase. If I can do that,
					I can do anything.</p>
				<p>Now for the rumor. One of the men
					who is stationed here permanently heard one
					of the officers remark that 5 of the men from
					the battery were to be moved out within a

				<pb n='4' facs="/sites/default/files/2025-08/0004_1942-09-30_004_0.jpg"/>

					few days. My name was one of those mentioned.
					(There were 5 of us who were interviewed that time for
					officers training.)
				</p>
				<p>
					I saw Roscoe Brownell tonight, and he
					tells me that he has been told to turn in his
					equipment tomorrow. That he too is being moved!
					He saw Paul Johnson, + Paul is in a division
					where all are shipped out after 6 weeks to
					officers training. He thinks that's where he is
					going. Maybe, I'll be there too.
				</p>
				<p>
					I do know for a fact that they have a
					one-month school here for men who are to
					go to officer's school at the end of that 1 month's
					training. Maybe that's where I'll be soon. But
					I've had no official notice as yet -- only this
					rumor. Perhaps, by the time this letter reaches
					you, I'll be moved. If I do change address,
					I shall telegraph you immediately.
				</p>
				<p>
					If I do leave, it will be with some
					misgiving, for I'm just beginning to
					really enjoy myself with this group, and
					I've made some fine friends in F-10-4</p>
					<closer>With love,
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>

				<div><p>
					P.S. -- We are scheduled for another overnite hike tomorrow and Friday. This time
					we are to go twice as far as last time.
				</p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
