<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter DATE</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Section II-3rd Platoon Battery A, 15th Battation, 5th Regiment FARC
						Dec 16, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother + Dad</salute>
            </opener>
            <p> Well, as I told you I might be, I've been moved. The new address is above. But I
					doubt if I'm here very long, so don't write. I don't expect to get any mail now
					until some few days after I get to Sill. Anything that should have been sent to
					D - 8 - 3 will be transferred here -- of course -- but will probably arrive here
					after I leave and then be transferred on to Sill. Incidently, if you wrote a
					Sunday letter it will fall in that class, for I didn't get it. </p>
            <p> However Amanda Miller's box did arrive just about an hour before I moved here --
					so I won't need to worry about that. I also received a 2 lb box of Purity candy
					from the O.E.S. I think it was so nice of them and I've already written a note
					of thanks to Kathryn Krowl -- she is still Sect., isnt she? Did I tell you I got
					a box of tookies from Lib? I've had cards from Mr. Thompson, Clarence Comstock,
					Howard Broscies, the Fishers, Fred Shoffer, Mr. Busser, The Rotary Club, Mr.
					&amp; Mrs. Stall, &amp; Mrs. Mathias. </p>
            <p> I also had a card from the Higgin's. It included a dollar. I've written to thank
					them. But what tickles me is that she evidently wasn’t convinced by your
					argument, Mother, <pb n="2"/> for she said it was to get yourself something to
					eat. </p>
            <p> Monday back in D - 8 - 3 I got up at 4:00 and was on my feet until 10:00 at
					night -- busy every minute. I was on K.P. in the morning. In the afternoon they
					put me on a landscaping detail - we shoveled clay. And in the evening we were
					closely supervised to see that a thorough clean-up job was done to get the
					barracks ready for the new cycle. I wish someone had pleased it up for us when
					we came in a few months ago. At any rate, by time for bed I was pretty tired. </p>
            <p> Yesterday, however, they forget about me. I got up in the morning, and after
					policing the barracks loafed for the rest of the day. </p>
            <p> Last night we moved over here -- and I can truthfully say that I was never so
					glad to leave any place in my life as I was D - 8 - 3. I didn't begin to tell
					you the things we had to do there and the guff we had to swallow. Too many of
					the officers and N.C.O.'s thought themselves little tin Gods. </p>
            <p> The new place is wonderful. When we arived here we discovered that the Sarge had
					already made our beds. Everything was clean and neat and the officers and men
					are fine. It is well ordered and well run. It's worth it not to go to Sill last
					Sunday just to be here to see what a really good outfit can be like. It's even a
					lot better than F - 10 - 4. </p>
            <p> Today we sampled the chow -- and its really good. This cook knows what he's
					doing. He's making <pb n="3"/> doughnuts for supper -- I'm anxious to taste
					them. They have nothing for us to do here except wait for shipment. So all we've
					done all day is act as table waters at noon and this evening. This morning four
					of us played bridge from 9 til 11:30 -- the 1st I've played since I left home, I
					think. This afternoon I got a haircut and wrote letters. </p>
            <p> Now don't count on it -- but we may be getting passes. In fact I just may be
					home before this letter. The battery Ccmmander is trying to see what he can do. </p>
            <p> They say there is not to be another shipment to Ft. Sill until after Xmas. In
					the case, I may even get an furlough and be home for the holiday. However, I'll
					be plenly satisfied with even a pass for 3 days. I guess, we'll just have to
					wait and see. At any rate, I don't mind not going to Sill nearly so much since
					I'm in this new outfit. </p>
            <p> It began to rain about 10 o'clock -- and about 1:30 it changed to snow. Now the
					ground, roofs, trees, etc. are covered. Just like Pa. I guess this will be our
					white Christmas. But I suppose it won't last long. </p>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <p> I guess that's all the news. I hope I do go home before this letter. </p>
            <p> Oh yes, I wanted to ask you. Forrest Brown wrote that a letter I had written to
					him was to be reprinted in the Bucknellian. Will you save that issue and send it
					to me when you get my address?</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Yours,</salute>
               <signed>John</signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>P.S. There is no phone here -- so you can't phone me as we had arranged.
						Perhaps I'll get a chance to call you from some place else if I don't get
						home.</p>
            </postscript>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
