<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter DATE</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>D - 8 - 3 FARC Dec 10, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother + Dad,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Well, I guess I've passed. I finished my exams today. I had no trouble at all so
					far as knowing what was wanted was concerned. However, I may have made any
					number of those silly little errors in arithmetic -- so I won't be sure til I
					get my certificate on Saturday morning at graduation. </p>
            <p> I'm sending home a box tomorrow. It includes my civilian shoes, the math books,
					a tin candy box, and another bunch of letters. Please store the shoes away for
					me. I'm told I won't be allowed to have them at Sill. If I am, then you can send
					them to me. At any rate, I'll want them again in April when I get my commission. </p>
            <p> Please return Prof. Richardson's math books for me. They were of a great deal of
						<pb n="2"/> help. I was surprised that I remembered as much as I did from
					high school trig and geometry. Guess our high school isn't so bad after all. So
					with the help of the books, I soon bringing up all I need to know. The real
					College Algebra look is my own, as is the book of tables. You can store both of
					them in my box on the attic again. </p>
            <p> As for the letters - just put them with the others I sent home. </p>
            <p> I'm inclosing Cousin Emma's check. Please deposit it to my account. Thanks. I'll
					wait til I get to Sill to thank her O.K.? </p>
            <p> The underwear is fine. If anything a bit too large - but drinkage will take care
					of that. Thank you very much. If you want to get me any more, however, just get
					ordinary shorts -- I now have enough heavy and light-heavy. </p>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <p> Mother, don't worthy about my health. I know how to take care of myself. My cold
					is completely gone -- and I've never felt better in my life. </p>
            <p> I still haven't received Amanda Miller's box -- and I have no way of picking it
					up. It's lost in the rush somewhere. I suppose it will turn up here after I've
					left. </p>
            <p> All of the boys in my class -- and all in the barracks with me (except those who
					fail) are on the shipment list for Sill this Sunday. I am not. There is still a
					chance for they may need replacements for those who fail. I do hope I can go
					this week -- for there is a good gang here and we could have a grand time on the
					train. </p>
            <p> D - 8 - 3 gets a complete new set of soldiers on Monday. So all of us who are
					here now must get out. I'm not shipped <pb n="4"/> to Sill, I will have to move
					somewhere in the 15th Bn, 5th Regiment, to await shipment. So don't write to me
					again until you get my new address. I'll be moved one way or the other on
					Sunday. I'll try to phone or telegraph where I am. </p>
            <p> I'm glad you told Marion H. off at Bee. But for my part I'm inclined to agree
					with her. The food we get is the best quality there is, but the cooks certainly
					mess it up until its hardly fit to eat. At any rate, that's not Roosevelt's
					fault. We get good ingredients -- it's just the cooks who are bad. Remember, you
					only sampled Service Club food which we have in pay for. </p>
            <p> You didn't give me John Stahl's address -- so I don't know how to look him up.
					And I'll be leaving soon so I don't suppose I'll get it in time to see him. At
					any rate, I'll bet he's over on the main post. </p>
            <pb n="5"/>
            <p> I've certainly been on the heavy end of the mail lately. The box from the church
					arrived (I recognized Mother's handwiting) and was much appreciated. Who should
					I thank? Guess a letter to Rev. Ostergren would be in order then he can thank
					the proper group for me! It was a very nice box, incidently. </p>
            <p> I also had a box of popcorn from Isabel, I think -- from William sport anyway.
					Mary + Allen sent a tin box of Xmas Cookies -- and were they good! Mary
					certainly is a good cook, Tommy &amp; Agnes sent me a box of very nice
					handkerchiefs for Xmas. I shall write to thank everyone this week-end -- if I'm
					not on my way to Sill by then. </p>
            <p> Cards &amp; letters have been coming too. Particularly from the Masons. I'll
					list then. Russell Stover, John L. Strassner of Indiana, Pa. Harold Miller,
					George Irland, William Rishel -- and a letter from <pb n="6"/> W.B. Smith in
					Philadelphia. I've also had Xmas cards from Neil &amp; Ruth Baker + Mrs Jacob
					Miller. I think I did tell you that I had a nice Letter from Sam Wolfe. </p>
            <p> Aunt Nelle, Isabel, Aunt Stell, Harry Stein, and Aice also have written. </p>
            <p> Tomorrow I'll turn in my books and polish everything off at Center School.
					Saturday morn we have a little ceremony at the Center theather. After that, I
					guess it will be KP again, unless I'm shipped to Penn. </p>
            <p> However there is a faint chance that in the new outfit (15th Bn.), I may be able
					to get a pass. </p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Anything can happen in the army Yours,</salute>
               <signed>John</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
