<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter December 13, 1942</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>D-8-3 FARC Dec 13, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother + Dad</salute>
            </opener>
            <p> Well I'm still here - and from the looks of things, I will be for another full
					week. Most of the others leave taught at 8:00. I'm the only one left behind -
					and allready I'm scheduled for K.P. tomorrow. I'm sticking close to the barracks
					today in hopes of yet being included on the shipping list - but I'm afraid it is
					a foolish wait. </p>
            <p> Graduation exercises yesterday were featured by a speech by the general. He also
					handed out the diplomas and shook hands with each of us. As usual I was last in
					line -- and he stopped me to remark, I hope you won't be last in your class at
					Sill. I felt like saying, "I hope I won't be the last to get to Sill." </p>
            <p> I think I did pretty well for a mere A.B. I didn't get a single U all the way
					through, and most of my finals were perfect or almost perfect papers. </p>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <p> My mail continues to be heavy. Friday I heard from Helen Stanley and Mrs.
					Thompson, with cards from Dad, Bill Frederick, and one signed by the officers of
					the lodge. Saturday I had a card from Pres. Marts, Tommy + Agnes, and one from
					Allen + Mary which icluded $2. -- also a letter from Janet Bold. Geturde
					Shaffer's little gift arrived and turned out to be a pocket sized chess set --
					very nice of her. Todany I got a box of Christmas cookies, nuts, + candy from
					Lib Dyer. Also cards from Mr. Thompson, Clarence Comstock, Howard Brocius, the
					Fishers, and the B.V. Mother's Association. </p>
            <p> I spent yesterday and today answering letters. I think tomorrow night I shall go
					to a movie -- if I get out of K.P. in time. Amanda Miller's box hasnt yet
					arrived. Guess it is lost between here and F - 10 - 4. I it would probably
					arrive soon. Wrote her today in answer to her letter &amp; told her that it
					would probably arrive soon. Guess that's all the news -- since I havent been
					anywhere. I'll write again Wednesday. But don't you write to this address after
					Wednesday,</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Yours,</salute>
               <signed>John</signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>P.S. -- Didn't get to church today -- I wanted to stick around in case they
						decided to add me to the shipping list.</p>
            </postscript>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
