<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-10-10</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>
						<orgName>D-8-3 FARC</orgName>
						<date>Oct 14, 1942</date>
				</dateline>
				</opener>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad</salute>
					<p>I suppose Grandma has gone to Aunt Stella's
					by this time. I shall try to write to her at least once
					a week -- probably on the week-end.
				</p>
				<p>
					After you promised not to send insured
					mail again, the candy came that way. Thanks
					anyway, it came in handy even if I did have to
					wait an extra day to get it. I also got a large box
					of candy from Aunt Lillian &amp; a box from Aunt
					Nelle (mailed in Harrisburg). All in all I've
					had about 8 pounds of candy this week. Of course,
					the boys accounted for most of it.
				</p>
				<p>
					As you suggested. I shall keep the can.
					It comes in handy to keep candy, etc. in. I haven't
					even opened your last shipment of canned goods.
					yet. I'll save it for some day when the chow
					isnt so good.
				</p>
				<p>
					I thank you so much for the money order.
					Mother. I didn't need it yet -- and I don't think
					I will. But there are 15 more days til payday --
				
				<pb n='2'/>
					and things would undoubtedly have been a bit
					light at the end of the month. I shall use it to
					treal myself to dinner at the Service Club now
					and again.
				</p>
				<p>
					"Time" has begun to arrive direct from
					the publishers, so you needn't send it any
					more. Thanks for the last one and for "The Bucknellian".
					I haven't received the weekly from the C.A. for
					several weeks. I don't know too many of the
					names in the Bucknellian myself. I did keep
					up a bit last year -- but from now on I'll
					be completely in the fog.
				</p>
				<p>
					Somene sent the church program (other than
					the one you included) to both Brownell and I. I
					wonder if Rev. Ostergren did it! At any rate
					it was sent to the old address. Bether tell him
					we have both moved. I had a nice letter from
					Jimmy O. too.
				</p>
				<p>
					Thanks for sending on the card from
					Leon. I've meant to write to him, but didn't
					have his address. I also had a letter from
					Dick Sharp. He's been drafted -- goes in
					Oct. 22nd.
				</p>
				<p>
					It sounds to me as though the whole
					town has heard my record-letter by this time.
				<pb n='3'/>
					I'll have to make another next time I go into
					town so you can play it when told one
					wears out.
				</p>
				<p>
					I really don't need a sweater. I purchased
					a sweat jersey at the PX that I wear under my
					fatigue jacket on cold days. You can get me
					one for Xmas, if you really want to, however.
					It must be olive drab shade. Any kind will do.
					And just get the largest size they have -- 42 or
					44 ought to fit pretty well -- nothing smaller,
					however.
				</p>
				<p>
					I have plenty of handkies and I can get socks
					at the PX as I need them. They must be
					regulation--so don't try to buy them for me. I
					I get to be an officer, I will have to buy my own
					uniform and there will be plenty I'll need. You
					can help out their if you want.
				</p>
				<p>
					How was the tea? Are you able to get
					goods for Xmas, Dad? And is business
					still holding up.
				</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
				<p>
					The weather here has been a bit cooler. We go
					into our winter uniforms tomorrow. So far we
					have been in cottons -- a sort of twist like my old
					boy scout uniform. The winter uniform is wool.
					We shall see now whether I break out in a rash.
				</p>
				<p>
					It seldom snows down here, they tell me. It
					just rains -- and judging from that -- we've had
					winter weather. It's been raining or drizzling
					since Sunday. One time last year it rained
					for three weeks straight.
				</p>
				<p>
					I walked guard duty Monday night and
					Tuesday. Got soaked to the skin, of course,
					dispite my raincoat. But I took a hot shower
					and didn't even get a cold -- actually lost the
					small one I had. My ankles better too.
				</p>
				<p>
					Guard duty wasn't bad. I walked from 5 to
					7 and from 11 to 1 twice a day -- both A.M. +
					P.M. that is. The night a shifts were lonely +
					nothing exciting happened.
				</p>
				<p>
					Brownell has been up for his Center
					School interview. We may get into school
					this week. It looks as though they are going
					alphebetically. At that rate I'll be here til the
					very last.
				</p>
				<closer>
					
					<signed>Yours,
					John.</signed>
				</closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
