<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-09-15</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n="1"/>

				<opener><dateline>Sept. 15 1942 F-10-4-F.A.R.C. Fort Bragg, N.C.</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother, Dad, &amp; Grandma -</salute></opener>
				<p>Just a brief note, for I don't have much time this evening. I was called out
					of the outfit today for an interview. It turns out that sooner or later I will
					be asked to apply for Officer's Training.</p>
				<p> The Lt. today told me that I may be asked to apply within a few days - although
					he told some of the other boys, 3 mo.; and one boy 3 weeks. My own judgement is
					that I shall have to finish basic training with the outfit 1st. But I must be
					prepared whenever they decide to give me the chance. Hence this note.</p>
				<p>The Lt. suggested that I bone up on math, since I haven't had any use or
					practice in that field for several years. He was a lawyer in civil life. The
					other boys who had interveens had to answer a few problens. But when he saw that
					I had completed a year in law school he said, &quot;Anyone who can pass the 1st
					year in law school shouldn't have any <pb n="2"/> trouble with math”. And
					that was all there was to it.</p>
				<p>Now - what I want you to do for Tme. First - send me my College Algebra book and
					also the small, paper-bound, bord of log tables. Both are in my box in the
					attic. The Algebra book is red. The log tables are brown and about 1/2 wich to
					3/4 inch thick. </p>
				<p> Second - I have written Prof. Richardson to advise we what to use to study Trig
					+ Geometry. I told him you would call him to find out what book or books to buy.
					Whatever he suggests, send along too. You  can probably get them at Keelers. I
					have to put you to all that trouble but I know you'll be glad to do it. The
					sooner I can start reviewing, the better off. I'll be. There are math
					classes here too - but I think I'd do better by studying on my own too.</p>
				<p>I'm glad Bob + Ruth are taking th apt. I thought of them, but I supposed
					they would be settled by now. I'm sure you'll like them, for I liked
					them both. </p>
				<pb n="3"/>

				<p>I guess I spoke too soon about my hay fever. It was bad today. I didn't feel
					bad, but I sneezed quite a bit and my nose ran continuously. My eyes were all
					right. It has been so dry for a week now, and the sand comes up in clouds of
					dust. I wish it would rain, then I'd have no trouble. </p>
				<p> I'm so glad you didn't take boys. You would never get fellows like
					Alex and Bill again.</p>
				<p>Yes, I make my own bed. And there daren't be a single wrinkle in it. Thank
					you for the church program. Now I have Brownell's address too I shall save
					the papers for him.</p>
				<p>There were only five girls in the class at law school, so it wouldn't it be
					hard to guess which one said that. I'll have to send them each a quarter -
					just to make sure I get the right one.</p>
				<p>We had chicken on Sunday too, and I got white meat - so you &amp; Grandman
					needn't worry.</p>
				<p>I wish Peak Painter [?]  were here to explain this artillery business to me. As
					yet I <pb n="4"/> haven't the slightest idea what it is all about We re
					still drilling on fundamentals.</p>
				<p>I'm going to ask you to do something else for me. I want to keep with the
					news. I don't have time to read the paper every day and the papers here
					don't cover everything anyway. So would you subscribe to Time magazine for
					me and have it sent to this address. I'd appreciate it very much. The Post
					Exchange news stand doesn't carry anything but cheap pulp magazines, and I
					have to have something better. I guess there's not enough demand for them
					to stock magazines like Time. Thank you! </p>
				<p> Also, I'm going to retract my request not to send me food. I still
					don't want it for myself - but all the other fellows have offered me things
					from boxes - and I'm ashamed not to have something to offer them now + then
					too. I hope I haven't asked for too much in this letter. </p>
				<closer><salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
