<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 

        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter DATE</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
           
				<opener>
					<dateline>D - 8 - 3 FARC
					Nov 25, 1942</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute>
				</opener>
			 <p>		
			 	Thanksgiving eve -- and since
					tomorrow is a holiday -- I'm taking off time
					to write a few letters.
				</p>
            <p>
					I'm so glad you are finally getting
					that nursing course, Mother. I know you
					have been thinking about it for some time --
					and goodness knows, you may have good
					use for it -- tho, we hope not. And you
					won't have any trouble studying, I know.
				</p>
            <p>
					So Lib finally got a preacher too.
					These ministers -- I don't understand how
					they do it. But Bud is a nice fellow,
					and Lib and he should make a good pair. 
					There goes another of my old standbys. I'm
					more of a bachelor than ever. So there will
					be no one to trot around with but the
					younger generation -- and I'm afraid
					they won't appreciate the gray-haired
					old guy I'll be by the time this is over.
				</p>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <p>
					Poor Dave -- but he'll have to make the 
					the regular army for discipline -- so he may be
					better off than I was, at that. I imagine
					we'll have a lot to talk about when we get
					together again.
					I'm glad Jr. made the band. Now best of it. The Air Corps is nothing compared to
					I suppose they are all happy again. I
					bet the poor kid heard he was to be transferred
					and didn't know where too.
				</p>
            <p>
					I know you enjoyed Aunt Va's
					visit. I only wish I could have been there.
					too.
				</p>
            <p>
					I've been pondering what to do about
					Xmas presents, Xmas cards, etc. It is
					almost impossible for me to do any shopping
					in Fayettsville -- and it is impossible for
					me to get wrapping material to send things
					home. I think probably the best I can do is
					to have you do my shopping for me. You
					buy presents for me to give Alice, Aunt Stella, 
					Grandma, Cousin Emma, and for yourself
					and Dad. Then let me know the cost and
            <pb n="3"/>
           I'll send you a check. I just don't know
					what else to do. The problem is particularly
					difficult since I shall probably be moving
					out of here just before the holidays.
				</p>
            <p>
					I don't know what to do about
					Xmas cards either. If you think it is
					allright, I won't send any. For to send to
					one &amp; not all, wouldn't be right, and
					it would keep me going for a week to
					remember everybody. Could you just
					include me in the card you + Dad send?
				</p>
            <p>
					I think too, that it would be
					best not to send Xmas mail to
					me here. So pass the word around. I
					certainly won't be here after Dec. 18th -- and
					mail before that will be undependable
					because of the rush. I suggest, that if you
					do have anything to send, you wait til
					after I go to Sill + then send it there.
				</p>
            <pb n="4"/>
            <p>
					Any mail arriving at Bragg after I
					leave will undoubtedly be a month
					following me. And I shan't be able to carry
					any packages or presents with me.
				</p>
            <p>
					I have hopes for a pass -- 3 day -- when
					I get out of Center School. I'll probably
					get it Monday or Tuesday and definitely
					have to be back Saturday morning. It should
					give me about 30 hours at home. So don't
					make any big plans for the week of Dec 12-18.
					On the other hand, I may go to Sill on the
					12th -- in which case you want see me
					until April.
				</p>
            <p>
					Let me know what you think
					about the Xmas business and don't
					forget what I said about mail. I don't
					want to have a lot of letters, etc following
					me across the south.
				</p>
            <closer>
					<salute>Yours,</salute>
					John
				</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
