<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter DATE</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Officers Canidate Class #56 Ft. Sill, Okla Dec 27, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute>
            </opener>
            <p> I didn't get a chance to phone on Christmas, but I did send a telegram from
					Lawton, on Saturday night. Hope you received it. </p>
            <p> Life moves pretty rapidly here. Christmas day was warm and clear -- more like
					Easter -- and I relaxed a bit, and saw a movie. Since then, however, I've been
					really on the go. </p>
            <p> We're up at 6:00 -- police up -- clean the hut -- eat -- etc. and move off to
					class at 8:30. The class rooms are 2 miles away -- so we really hike. Classes
					run from 9 to 12:50 and from 2 til 5:50. We get about 10 minutes for lunch and
					supper. The evenings are spent in study -- it's required -- so there will be no
						<pb n="2"/> renning around - and no monies, except on well-ends. We have to
					be in our huts from 7:30 to 10:30. After that we can go to the toilet. if we
					want to Not to be vulgar - but most of us do went to for that is actually the
					only charge we get all day </p>
            <p> Right now I'm in Motors. The course is much more detailed them at Bragg. I'll be
					since cleep in grease all week. When I'm finished I'll really know what makes
					the blameal trucks work. yesterday, for instance, we took the wheels off and
					repached the bearing, adfisted brades, etc. </p>
            <p> I today we moved to our new 6 man but only there are only 3 men in mine. My
					roomrates for the next 12 weeks seem very nice - one is from Petroit Zwodnik -
					and the other, Young, is from Oblahoma. I'm sure we'll get along. </p>
            <p> I had a card from the Grices - inclosing a dollar -- and a card and a check for
					$ 2 from <pb n="3"/> Uncle Tom &amp; Aunt Hesther. I'm inclosing it. Please
					deposit it to my account. I also had a card from the Beards. Thank all of them
					for me -- of course, I'm writing Grices + Uncle Tom. </p>
            <p> I didn't get to church this morning because we had to take a math test and then
					move. Unless they think of something else for us to do next week, I'll try to go
					then. I've looked around and discovered the chapel. They never heard of the 40
					hr. week here. </p>
            <p> I did get into Lawton last night I was going to buy a foot locker (trunk), but
					couldn't find one to suit me. So I got a suitcase instead. I'll have to get a
					foot locker later but the sutease will do in the meantine. And I need the
					suitcase anyway. When I leave here I'll have enough stuff to fill the trunk, my
					Gladstone <pb n="4"/> and the new bag. </p>
            <p> Incedently, we've figured it out, and I shall finish here (barring accidents) on
					March 18th. So I'll be home for 10 days beginning about March 20th. </p>
            <p> Guess that's all for now. I'll write again as soon as I can -- but it may not be
					til next Sunday. </p>
            <p> Send the local papers, Bucknellians, etc - and any pertinent item clippings.
					I've lost contact with what's going on at home. </p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Love,</salute>
               <signed>John</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
