<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-11-08</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>
						<name>D-8-3 FARC</name>
					<date>Nov. 8, 1942</date>
					</dateline>
					<salute>Dear <persName>Mother</persName> + <persName>Dad</persName></salute>
				</opener>
				<p>
					Well the Yanks invaded Africa
					yesterday. I suppose Dave will say more
					than ever now that they were just waiting for
					him to go ahead. I hope he doesn't have too much
					trouble -- but I imagine I will be harder for
					him to adjust to a new situation.
				</p>
				<p>
					I shall be looking forward to seeing
					you this week-end. Dont forget to bring
					my candid camera.
				</p>
				<p>
					I suggest that you come out to
					the Guest House about 2:30 or 3:00
					Friday afternoon. I'll tell them to expect
					you at the control gate about that time.
					Then you'll have a chance to get settled by
					5:30 - when I'll come over to the guest
					house to see you.
				</p>
				<pb n='2'/>
				<p>
					Yesterday just after supper I went up
					to C-6-2 to see Will Duck. I couldn't
					place the name -- but as soon as I saw
					him I recognized a Lewisburg face. We
					had quite a chat. He seems to like it all right
					I told him you folks were coming down,
					so perhaps Dad can go up with me to see
					him next Saturday.
				</p>
				<p>
					I hope you had a nice trip to
					Harrisburg. But, Mother, you certainly
					are forgetful. You said you hadn't been out
					of town in 6 mo. Don't forget our trip
					to Penn State and down to Lancaster.
				</p>
				<p>
					I had a letter from Jean Dyer this
					week. She asked me to be sure &amp; tell you.
					It seems she was in the store homceoming
					and she thinks Dad was mad because she
					hadnt written to me.
				</p>
				<p>
					I also had a letter from Janet
					Bold.
				</p>
				<pb n='3'/>
				<p>
					I got up early this morning and
					ran the obstacle course just for the fun of it
					with 3 other boys. Then I  went back to bed
					intending to sleep til nine -- instead I overslept
					and didn't get awake til 10:30. It was
					too late for church so I listened to several
					radio services.
				</p>
				<p>
					Yesterday inspection the Lt. pointed
					to me &amp; remarked to the Sgt. "There's a good
					looking soldier." I got a big kick out of it
					and the boys have been razzing me ever since.
				</p>
				<p>
					Rumors are hot + heavy around
					here this week. It is now wispered that
					the officers training program is to be transferred
					from Ft. Sill to Fort Bragg on Dec 15th.
					In this case I'd never get to Okla. but
					would get my commission here instead.
				</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
				<p>
					It is definite that at the end of 5
					weeks our battery is to be completely
					disbanded and the quarters used as
					barracks for O.C.S. men in the Center School.
					So I know for sure I'll be out of here or
					wlse in Center School myself within that
					time. Rumor has it that the whole Regiment
					is to be used used then -- which would fit in
					with the lot rumor.
				</p>
				<p>
					Since the battery is disbanding -- the
					battery fund has to be spent before we
					leave. The fund is accumulated by
					 deducting about 50 ¢ from each man every
					payday. There is about $ 1000 there now. 
					We have to spend it in the next 5 weeks --
					so we expect to eat better for awhile.
					Already they have started to have "Coke"
					cigarettes + cigars with meals. I
					enjoy the "Coke" but the tobacco is just
					a waste of money as far as I'm
					concerned. I suppose they'll buy beer next.
				</p>
				<pb n='5'/>
				<p>
					Mail call just brought your
					Harrisburg card, Dad. Too bad you
					couldn't buy any goods. I also got
					a fine letter from Leon Arbogast and
					a note from Ted. Still no note from
					Ken Dannenhauer. If you see Miss Henderson
					Mother, ask her if she has heard anything
					about him. Something must have happened.
				</p>
				<p>
					I shan't write again until after I
					see you -- and since that's the news
					for now --
				</p>
				<closer>
					<salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed><persName>John</persName></signed>
				</closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
