<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter DATE</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>FORT BRAGG, N. C. officers Candàle School Class #56 &amp; t. Sill,
						Opla. Dec 24, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother &amp; Dad -</salute>
            </opener>
            <p> It was good to hear your voice again an Monday, Mother. I'm only sorry I didn't
					call when you were home, Dasl. I should have known. </p>
            <p> yours an mail letly arrived today.son's air mail letter of the 14th was the only
					word I got at Biagg last week. I may I have tomorrow, if I can. But even if I
					don't, I shall be thinking of you. I's just like you Mother to have a big dinner
					and send half of it out. God bless you for keeping the Christians spirit going. </p>
            <p> What are you going to sell for the rest of the year, Bad. From all reports
					you're just <pb n="2"/> about sold out. Better by bonds while you can. </p>
            <p> I hope the box I sent has arrived this time. I have another first about ready.
					It contains letters, cards, another volume of my diary, which you are free to
					read, and a 10 ¢ photograph I had taken in the station at Tulsa, Okla. I'll
					probably mail it off next weekend. </p>
            <p> I didn't even know Hays Nesbit was planning to be married. Who's the girl?
					Someone from Rochester? Too bad about the mumps. Keep me informed. </p>
            <p> Alice told me about James, Jr. Good for him! Hope he likes it. </p>
            <p> You can send on my Xmas box now if you haven't already. I'll combine Xmas &amp;
					New Year's for a real celebration! </p>
            <p> I began to tell about the trip out in Alice's letter. I'll finish it in yours.
					Here goes. <pb n="3"/> After a brief stop in Memphis, we moved across the
					Mississippi by moonlight and into Arkansas. Since we had missed connections, we
					went around the long way. I awoke in the morning. (I shared a lower that night)
					in Springfield, Mosouri. </p>
            <p> The western side of the Mississippi is much nicer than the eastern side in the
					south. It's good to see rich black soil again -- and mpainted barns &amp;
					houses. The country reminds me a great deal of the midwest. But it is even more
					level. There is something beautiful about the plains -- but I'll still take Pa's
					mountains. </p>
            <p> After dinner in the Diner, we pulled into Tulsa, Okla. Tulsa is a wonderful <pb n="4"/> City. It is modern, clear, and neat, and the people are very
					hospitable. We roamed the downtown streets for over an hour. I've never seen so
					many women in slacks. </p>
            <p> We hit Oklahoma City just before supper. We didn't get out of the station, but
					it looked like a good place too. There seemed to be oil wells in everybodies and
					his neighbor's back yard. The skyline was dotted with them. </p>
            <p> We pulled into Sill a little after 8:00 and came right over to the area. We
					sleep until Sunday in 15 man hutments heated by gas stoves. </p>
            <p> After Sunday I'll move into a four man hut. That will be my permanent home. </p>
            <p> Sill seems very nice, but I'll have to dig. I don't know how much time I'll <pb n="5"/> have to write. So if you don't hear from me for awhile, don't worry.
					It will take me a little while to get used to the pace. I'll write next Sunday
					at least and every Sunday thereafter -- but I can't promise about the week-days. </p>
            <p> I'm pretty tired -- so I think I shall close now and go back to the hut and turn
					in. The weeks ahead are going to be hard. The 1st two weeks will be hardest for
					we have 10 days of motors and then 5 days of material. After that they get into
					academic subjects where I'll be able to shine a bit more. </p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Happy New year</salute>
               <signed>John</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
