<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
        ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter: December 2, 1942</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>D-8-3 FARC Dec 2, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Another Center School week is half over and I'm still going strong. 10 boys in my
					class failed and have to start over again. There will be more taking the course
					over at the end of the four weeks. </p>
            <p> On payday Monday I drew $41.90 - that's 50 less $6.60 for insurance and $1.50
					for laundry. I shall not send any home, for I will need it when transferring to
					Sill, etc. However, when my Xmas Club check comes -- send it along and I'll sign
					it and send it back. You can deposit that for me. </p>
            <p> Mother, if Reel Brough thinks the “regulars” in undewear will be big enough,
					then get those. If not, then get me the half length or quarter length -- that
					mcome just to the knees and down the arms halfway. If they don't have those --
					then <pb n="2"/> get ordinary shorts (plenty big)  and  polo or jersey type
					tops. O.K.? </p>
            <p> I'm glad Dad got a watch for me I shall be very proud of it. Do not send it or
					the iron, however, until I go to Sill. If I should get home, I'll bring it back
					with me. </p>
            <p> Chances are that I will not get home. Passes haven't been given out for the past
					two weeks. We can't even get a Raleigh pass anymore on week-ends. I haven't
					given up hope. However, the situation may change, so </p>
            <p> I haven't given up hope. I'm fairly certain that I won't be shipped to Sill on
					the 13th. The shipping list is unalphebetically -- and my name being what it is
					- I'll have to wait til the 20th. All of which means I'll be walking guard and
					doing K.P. for a week again -- unless I should get that pass. I'm going to see
					what I can do to go on the 13th, however, if passes continue to be scarce. </p>
            <pb n="3"/>
            <p> I had a letter from Ted. He tried for Officer's Training, but cant pass the
					physical. His blood pleasure is off and he is under- weight. But he seems just
					as pleased about it anyway. He's going to try to get to be a 1st Sergeant. At
					least he'll make out as well financially. </p>
            <p> I had a Xmas Card from the Wainwright's -- thank them for me if you see them,
					will you. (Mr. + Mrs. Maurice) Also had a letter from Amanda Miller. I have a
					worse time reading her writing than Emma H's -- but don't tell her. She says she
					is sending candy soon. Hope she has the right address. Her letter went to F-10-4
					and was forwarded. Haven't heard from Isabelle for a while but I guess she is
					busy. </p>
            <p> Thank you so much for the box of <pb n="4"/> food. The judge vanished
					immediately. The cookies are still holding out -- largely because I hid them. We
					all enjoy them a lot. The fellows all want to come home will me -- they know you
					are a good cook, Mother. </p>
            <p> It is cold again. And there is a brisk wind that carries half of the sand on the
					place with it. Every time you open your mouth you get a fist ful of sand between
					your teeth. I hope Oklahoma isnt like this. But they say winters are just as
					cold and windy there. </p>
            <p> We went to see a very fine movie this afternoon. It's to be shown to all the
					troops. It goes into the backgrounf of the war and explains how we got into this
					situation. Every man, woman + child in the U.S. should see it. It's lesson is
					this. 1. This war began in 1931 when Japan <pb n="5"/> went into Manchuria. 2.
					No people or nation is safe unless the whole world is safe. and living in peace.
					3. Because we failed to see how the killing of a few Chinese in Manchuria, or
					negros in Etheopia could effect us; Because we failed to protect them -- we find
					ourselves in this position today. All of us were very much impressed. </p>
            <closer> Guess that's about all the news -- <salute>Yours, John</salute>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
