<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter September 27, 1942</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>F-10-4 FARCH Sept. 27, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother + Dad and Grandma</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>I hadn't intended to write today, but there were a few things I forget to say on that
               talking record yesterday. </p>
            <p> Yes, the New York letter was a wedding announcement from Kern &amp; Penny. Please
               select a gift for me and send it off. I don't know where Penny is now but Janet Bold
               will know. you can call her at Honor House to find out. </p>
            <p> I had a nice note from Jeanne Haynes Thomas. She seemed quite pleased with the gift.
               All of your packages arrived safety -- </p>
            <p> including Reader's Digest and Time. I got a box of cakes from Aunt Edna too, I'll
               write later to thank her. I didn't have to pay postage on the Phi Beta Kappa paper,
               either. Fort Bragg does have a show, but it is carried only over small stations in
               N.C. <pb n="2"/> I'm quite sure you could not pick it up. Occasionally, one of the
               big programs broadcasts from here. Next time one comes, I’ll let you know in advance
               &amp; you can tune in. Yes -- a route marker is a sort of traffic cop. I had to stop
               all traffic while the convoy went through. </p>
            <p> The weather here has been just right -- but the southern boys think it's cold. K.P.
               today wasn't so awfully bad, but I'm quite tired. I cut my finger about fifty times
               while lutting squash and peeling spuds. Must close now - </p>
            <closer> Yours-- John</closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>P.S. Hope my voice sounds natural on the letter--record. Dont forget there is a
                  message on both sides.</p>
            </postscript>
            <postscript>
               <p>P.P.S. - I had a letter from Fred Shaffer, Cousin Emma, Isabele Bond, + a card
                  from the Steins.</p>
            </postscript>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
