<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-11-05</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>
						<date>Nov. 5, 1942</date>
					<name>D-8-3  FARC</name>
					</dateline>
					<salute>Dear <persName>Mother</persName> + <persName>Dad</persName>--</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>
					It was good to hear your voices
					Monday evening. I hope it didn't cost too
					much. Let me know what the phone company
					charged. If it's not too much, I may try
					it again sometime.
				</p>
				<p>
					I'm awfully sorry you had to change
					plans, etc, but it just cant be helped.
					The 1st Sgt. told us at retreat Monday
					that no passes would be issued this
					week-end, and that if we had friends or
					relatives coming we should tell them to
					stay home. We go on Regimental Guard
					Saturday and stay on til Monday -- so
					even if you had come the chances are
					I never could have seen you. On the other
				<pb n='2'/>				
					hand. I may be free most of the week-end
					but it just wasn't worth it to take the
					chance.
				</p>
				<p>
					I only hope we don't run into
					difficulties next week-end. But since
					I've had most of the details recently, there
					shouldn't be any trouble.
				</p>
				<p>
					I meant to write Monday, but the
					evening slipped by before I got a chance.
					Incidently, I went over right after
					the phone call &amp; made new restivations
					at the Guest House -- so we are all
					set for you here.
				</p>
				<p>
					Tuesday evening I went on
					prison guard and was on til 5:00
					on Wednesday. It wasn't too bad.
					We rode hard on prisoners who
					had been A.W.O.L. and deserters.
					We carried loaded guns and walked
				<pb n='3'/>				
					around behind them keeping them in view.
					If one had escaped from me, I would have
					had to serve out his sentence -- so we
					weren't too easy on them. Fortunately,
					there was no trouble -- although a man
					did escape on Monday -- and there was
					a riot on Sunday.
				</p>
				<p>
					Last evening I was told I was
					to appear before the examing board today
					for O.C.S. So I spent the evening
					shining shoes, etc. to get ready. Thus
					I didn't get a chance to write again.
				</p>
				<p>
					Incidently, Rosco, Brownell,
					is to start O.C.S. this Saturday. If 
					my name was Sak instead of Zeller,
					I'd probably be starting too.
				</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
				<p>
					The interview wasn't too bad. I got
					100 in both current events and in math
					and my English composition was
					satisfactory - so I'm sure I shall be
					going  to OCCS too before another month
					is out. The interviewing officer was
					an engineering graduate and like all
					engineers, he was amazed that an A.B.
					should know anything about math. It
					always makes me mad at these darn
					engineers -- they think A.B's don't know
					anything. Of course, I still have to pass
					another physical exam -- but if I don't
					pass it, I'll go into administration instead
					of artillery.
				</p>
				<p>
					Before I forget, please bring
					my candid camera with you when
					you came down. I believe it will
					be nice to have some pictures of
					the fellows -- as well as of myself.
				</p>
				<pb n='5'/>
				<p>
					I'm glad you made out so well
					with your "uninvited" homecoming
					guests. The Sholl's have been fine to me
					and it helps to repay. But then we've
					been me to Don too.
				</p>
				<p>
					I still don't know what we
					shall do when you come down -- but
					I suppose there will be so much to
					talk about that the time will pass all
					too swiftly. We can go to the
					movies. To church Sunday morning,
					and the band concert Sunday night.
					Your meals out here will have to be at
					the service club. You'll have to stand in
					line with all the soldiers -- but I guess
					you won't mind.
				</p>
				<pb n='6'/>
				<p>
					I think I shall go to the movies
					tonight to celebrate passing the board.
					So for now -- ! I'll write again
					Sunday, if I'm not too tired from
					guard duty.
				</p>
				<closer>
					<salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed><persName>John</persName></signed>
				</closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
