<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-10-06</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n="1"/>
				<opener>
					<dateline><name>FORT BRAGG, N. C.</name>
						<name>D-8-3 FANC</name>
						<date>Oct. 6, 1942</date></dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother, Dad, + Grandma</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>I'm disgusted -- but I'm going to stick it out here if it kills me. This new
					place is really a trial. They don't credit us with anything -- we are starting
					all over again. The past month goes for nothing at all. At any rate, after I
					finish 13 weeks here, I'll go to Canidate's school. And after 4 weeks there,
					I'll go to Fort Sill, Officers Training School. Then after 3 months I'll be
					eligible for a furlough if I'm still in the U.S. If you add that up you see that
					the chances are I won't get home before next August.</p>
				<p>Of course none of the above is certain. Even our officers don't know how long we
					are to be here -- but they're starting us in at the beginning anyway. One thing
					is certain -- we were all chosen as potential officers -- so we shall have a
					chance at Canidate's school here anyway. It's going to take a lot of patience to
					go through <pb n="2"/> cannoneers training -- after the interesting stuff we
					were getting at F-10 + tellephone communications. But if I want to be a feild
					artillery officer, I shall have to do it. This whole plan is an experiment, I
					understand, and its though being a guinea big -- but I'm going to do it.</p>
				<p>All of us are discouraged and would rather have stayed where we were for basic
					training - but this is the army. Moreover, when I think of the sacrafices the
					boys are making over there -- I can certainly stand this. Having told you about
					that, I'll answer your questions and deal with business. I have not yet received
					the regular subscription of Time. But you needn't send it to me any more. There
					are other news magazines here to keep me up to date until the regular
					subscription arrives. I'll let you know when it does.</p>
				<p>The cookies arrived -- also Isabelle's candy -- I went back to the old battery to
					get them -- and I appreciated them a great deal. So did the fellows! They're a
					fine bunch, but of course we don't know each other too well yet. Incidentally,
					don't send a good can again -- I have no place to keep it and </p>
				<pb n="3"/>
				<p> will only have to send it back. A cardboard box well wrapped will do -- or old
					coffee cans. Also -- please don't send packages insured or registered unless
					they contain some valuable. It is too difficult to get to the post office to
					collect it.</p>
				<p>Thanks for the picture of Dad in uniform. He must have borrowed it from Clair
					Groover -- who I think is on the other end of the line. But who is in the
					middle. (I'm enclosing the picture.)</p>
				<p>Save the record for me -- it will be fun to listen to it when I get back.
					Sometime when I go into Fayetteville again, I'll make another. I'm glad you
					enjoyed it. You can have the picture framed if you want to, I don't care -- just
					so you save it. When we get into winter uniform, I'm going to have my picture
					taken for you. I'm still waiting for you + Dad + Grandma to have pictures taken! </p>
				<pb n="4"/>
				<p> I think I did tell you once, but I am only about 2 blocks from the old barracks
					-- so I can go back often. But it not the same -- they're going ahead in they're
					cycle -- and I've gone back to start all over again.</p>
				<p>I'm writing at the Service Club. On their program this evening, private Marion
					Hargrove is appearing. He's the boy who wrote the best seller (humorous) on army
					life. It was featured in Life just 2 or 3 weeks ago. Alice must have read about
					it + you can borrow the copy of Life from her + read it too. He's not so
					humorous this evening -- he's trying to sell copy's of the army newspaper he's
					working for now.</p>
				<p>Had a letter from Janet Bold today. She tells me Jane + Tommy Walker have broken
					off. Had a card from Mand Nesbit. + a letter from Ben Kauffman. I don't have the
					time to answer either just now, so thank them for me.</p>
				<closer><signed>Yours, <name>John</name></signed></closer>

			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
