<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller Letter 1942-09-05</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline> Pvt. John F. Zeller<lb/> F-10-4 F.A.R.C.<lb/> Fort Bragg, N.C.</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother &amp; Dad + Grandma --</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>My address is above. We were put on quaranteen immediately upon arrival, so I could
               not phone or telegraph. We are confined to our company street. for 14 days. I'll get
               off on the 20th.</p>
            <p>I will not get a furlough until I have completed basic training, so I guess it will
               be impossible for me to get home before Christmas. </p>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <p> I am in a field artillery regiment. We will set up communications - telephone lines-
               for observors and between batteries. My years on the switchboard at BU got me in
               this.  I am the only one of our group here. The rest of the fellows are also in field
               artillery, but they are in other companies. I won't be able to see them before the
               two weeks are up and perhaps not then. There are 85,000 men here and the camp
               stretches for 25 miles.</p>
            <p>It is very nice, and I have no doubt but what I'll <pb n="3"/> like it. I'm going to
               work hard and do the very best I can.</p>
            <p>Basic training here lasts at least 8 weeks - perhaps 13 - then I'll be shipped
               somewhere else. I shall hope it will be to officers training school.</p>
            <p> The initials in my address means this - Battery F, 10th Batalion, 4th regiment,
               Field Artillery Replacement Center.</p>
            <p> There is a great deal to tell, but I went to get this out, as I know you're anxious.
               I'll write more details tomorrow <pb n="4"/> night. Mail at regular rate takes two
               days. This will go air mail. I'm posting it at 6:00 P.M. Let me know how soon you get
               it.</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Yours til tomorrow's letter,</salute>
               <signed>John</signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>P. S. Please send me a pair of slippers. I want the kind that consist of nothing
                  but a sole + heel + straps over the feet - made of rubber or [illegible] or
                  something like that. I'd prefer not leather, because I want them for the shower
                  room. Ken Wolfe is here, but of course I can't get out to see him. J.</p>
            </postscript>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
