<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-10-21</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline><name>D-8-3 FARC.</name>
					<date>Oct. 21, 1942</date></dateline>
					<salute>Dear <persName>Mother</persName> &amp; <persName>Dad</persName>--</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>
					I guess the flood to the north of us held
					up mail for a few days. Your letters arrived
					late too. I hope Dad didn't waste too much shoe
					leather going to the post office.
				</p>
				<p>
					Now to answer &amp; comment on your letters.
					No, I havent heard from Ken, and I can't under-
					stand it. I've written him twice. - I agree
					will you about Kern &amp; Benny - so do Don
					and Jannet. But everyman to his own choice. I
					really don't think he's being fooled much. He ought
					to know her by this time.
				</p>
				<p>
					This note ought to be arriving about the
					time Isabelle and Verna are with you. Give them
					my regards. I owe Isabelle a letter-but I'm
					afraid I won't get around to writing it for a
					few days.
				</p>
				<p>
					Let me know when Willard Remer is sent.
					There are a lot of volunteer officer canidadates here and
				<pb n='2'/>
					since they need artillery officers, he may end up
					here too.
				</p>
				<p>
					If you see Dave again, tell him not to
					worry. He's lucky if he doesn't get in with any
					worse fellows than Franklin &amp; Weston. He can
					take it from me. He's going to get his eyes opened!
					Lt. Colonel is the next rank above Major. It
					isn't too high, but it would be nice to have in front
					of one's name. It's still a long way from the highest
					officer though.
				</p>
				<p>
					Mother, I think you better just forget about
					the sweater.  At least until we see how things
					work out. If you are worried about Xmas
					presents, just give me money. I'll put it towards
					a radio or towards my officers uniforms when
					the time comes to get them.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please have my diploma framed and have
					it in the little room over the hall door.  I've
					reserved that spot for it. Try to get the same
					type frame as Dan Ross used on my A.B. diploma.
				</p>
				<p>
					One more thing and then I'll go into
					the news. I got a wedding announcement from
					Emily Ong Schreyer. That means another wedding
					present. Pick something out + send it. You ought
				<pb n='3'/>				
					to be able to get the address from any of the
					folks who work on the hill.
				</p>
				<p>
					I really cashed in on the mail this week.
					I had a nice box from the Grooner's. I salvaged
					the peanuts, but the candy, etc. went out in
					nothing flat. Boxes don't last long in our
					barracks. I had a nice note from Fred Igler--
					telling me of his visit to Bucknell--seeing
					you folks - the Demie House -- etc.
				</p>
				<p>
					Leo Arbogast wrote a most interesting
					not about the navy. I also heard from
					Peggy Kauffman, Forrest Brown, Mrs.
					Thompson,  Charlier Bard, and another card
					from Maude -- in addition to the regular
					letters from you folks &amp; from Alice.
				</p>
				<p>
					Yesterday we went on another overnite
					hike. It was cool so I wore long woolen
					underwear -- for the 1st time in my life, I think.
					I haven't developed a rash so far.
				</p>
				<p>
					Our packs were really heavy this time,
				<pb n='4'/>			
					for we carried two blankets -- extra underwear &amp; socks--
					field jacket, etc. The pack when made up was fully
					40 inches long. It bumped both my head and my
					sitter-downer with each step. Wt. -- 50 to 70 lb.
				</p>
				<p>
					In all we walked about 6 miles out and
					about 4 back. It rained -- and I really mean
					rained all night. I kept dry -- but my blankets
					didn't. It took all day back here to dry them.
				</p>
				<p>
					The rain stopped long enough in the morning
					for us to pack up &amp; start back. But it rained
					hard for about an hour and really got me soaked
					on the trip back. A good hot shower and dry
					clothes fixed me up, however, and I didn't even
					catch a sniffle.
				</p>
				<p>
					I made reservations for you at the Great
					House for Friday, Saturday &amp; Sunday. Nov. 6, 7, 8th
					O. K. ?
				</p>
				<p>
					I guess thats all of the news for now.
				</p>
					<closer><signed>So til Sunday--
					<persName>John</persName></signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
