<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-10-28</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>
						<date>Oct 28, 1942</date>
					<name>D-8-3 FARC</name>
					</dateline>
					<salute>Dear <persName>Mother</persName> + <persName>Dad</persName> --</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>
					First of all I must hasten to correct
					two impressions I left in my last letter
					which have been altered since Sunday. First
					of all, I recieved a box of candy just
					yesterday from Aunt Virgina. It had 
					been sent to F-10, but it was only mailed
					from Elysburg on the 22nd, so it wasn't
					too much delayed. Second, I saw Paul
					Johnson. He is in battery just two rows
					up the street. Why I haven't seen him before,
					I don't know. I met him at the dispatchers
					office Tuesday -- we were both driving
					trucks for the day.
				</p>
				<p>
					Thank you both for your letters.
					Be sure to send me your itinerary
					for the trip, as soon as you know
					definitely. I'll be able to meet you in
				<pb n='2'/>
					Fayettsville. Southern trains are usually
					late -- so don't be worried if the train is
					2 or 3 hrs behind schedule. I'll know what
					to expect. I'll be waiting at the station.
				</p>
				<p>
					If you haven't eaten on the train, we can
					have dinner together in Fayettsville before
					coming out to camp. We shall have to go
					to the control gate 1st to get your passes. After
					that you can come + go as your please.
				</p>
				<p>
					When do your plan to leave for home. The
					best northern train (usually 2 or 3hrs. late)
					is supposed to leave Fayettsville at 5:00
					or thereabouts.
				</p>
				<p>
					The gift for Emily Ong was quite
					satisfactory. Thank you.
				</p>
				<p>
					Ask Kenny if he has heard anything
					about Runkle -- Doc. Oliver's assistant
					last year who was at New Cumberland
					with me. I'm curious to know where
					he landed.
				</p>
				<p>
					I recieved your cookies, and
					as usual they didn't last long. The
				<pb n='3'/>				
					boys really enjoyed them -- and, of
					course, you know I did. Thanks also
					for the watch strap, Dad. I really needed
					it.
				</p>
				<p>
					I can't think of anything in particular
					I want you to bring down. But I'd
					like to suggest that in the next box
					you send, you can include a couple of
					glasses of jelly. I'm really hungry for
					some of it. We seldom have it at the mess hall.
				</p>
				<p>
					I have decided not to send the
					box home. I'll wait and send it with you
					folks when you go home.
				</p>
				<p>
					I purchased a new pen. A $5.00 Parker
					at the PX price of $3.00. It's not bad at
					all.
				</p>
				<p>
					Poor Dave. I have an idea he'll have
					a hard time adjusting himself. And being
					in limited service means he's likely
					to get many mire of the dirty degrading
				</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
				<p>
					jobs than the rest of us. But, of course, he
					may be better off too. He may get Air Corps
					Administration.
				</p>
				<p>
					The woolens have had no ill effects 
					as yet -- outside of a great deal of scratching
					anyway.
				</p>
				<p>
					All week so far I've been on drivers
					detail. I have not been assigned
					permanently to a truck -- but I have been
					assistant driver to another boy. We take
					turns driving his truck. Yes it is one of
					the big ones.
				</p>
				<p>
					We go down to Sanford, N.C.,
					about 35 miles away twice a day. We're
					bringing back the lumber from an abandoned
					CCC camp -- which is being used here.
					It's not a bad job -- but then you know
					how I like to drive.
				</p>
				<closer>
					<salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed><persName>John</persName></signed>
				</closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
