<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-10-10</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline><name>D-8-3 FARC</name>
					<date>Oct. 18, 1942</date></dateline>
				
					<salute>Dear <persName>Mother</persName> + <persName>Dad</persName> -</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>
					I was glad to hear you had decided to
					come down. I want you to see what army
					life is really like.
				</p>
				<p>
					I think it would be best if you would
					come Nov 6th. The earlier week-end is pay-day
					week-end and everything is so jammed that
					is almost impossible to go anywhere or do
					anything.
				</p>
				<p>
					I think it will be best too, if you
					stay at the guest house. There is little to do
					in Fayetteville, while out here you can
					see the camp and relax at the Service Club.
					I'll try to make arrangements this week, and
					I'll let you know.
				</p>
				<p>
					I told the fellows about the sugar
					and they all extend their appreciation to
					the rationing board. Quite a few of the fellows
				</p>
				<pb n='2'/>
				<p>
					have boughten cookies sent to them -- and while they
					don't last any longer them yours did -- the
					fellows appreciate the homenade kind more.
				</p>
				<p>
					Mother, you said Tommy looked so well in
					my old Brown suit. Why not give him my
					grey coat (the pants to that suit have been gone for
					some time) and my old blue suit (neither will
					be of any use to me any more and he ought to
					be able to use them for something).
				</p>
				<p>
					Let me know how Bud Ranch made
					out with the Air Corps will you?
					We signed the pay roll for the coming
					month. I don't know for sure, but I
					don't think they all going to deduct a bond
					from my pay. I don't think my application
					was in when my papers were transferred
					over here. I'll just send the money home
					and you can deposit it in my checking
					account. Later on, if I get to be an
					officer I'll have a bond dedeucted from
					my pay. I'll need the money in my
					checking account to buy officer's uniforms.
				</p>
				<pb n='3'/>
				<p>
					I'm inclosing the church program again.
					We have a new Chaplain. I don't like him as
					well as the last one, but he's all right.
				</p>
				<p>
					I need a new watch band. I'd like the
					same kind I have now. Will you either send
					one, or else bring I along when you come down.
					There's no hurry.
				</p>
				<p>
					We were given cards to fill out this week.
					I think they were to be used in filling out our
					application for officers training school. They
					asked which branch of the service we were interested
					in. I put down Air Corps Intelligence
					and Air Corps Administration. But I suppose
					I'll get Field Artillery.
				</p>
				<p>
					To become an officer I have to pass
					another physical, I'm a triful worried because
					of hay fever, but I heard something that
					makes me feel better. All otherwise
					qualified men, who fail to pass the physical
				</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
				<p>
					are sent to Officer's Training School in
					Army Administration. That's the school at
					Fort Washington you sent me the article
					about, Dad. So I'm no longer worred.
					I'd rather be there and anyway.
				</p>
				<p>
					I was on coal detail on Friday.
					We shoveled coal all day. My hands are
					covered with blisters. I certainly will be
					glad when I get to center school and leave
					all of these details behind. I can do this
					sort of thing when I have too and make the
					best of it, but I don't exactly like it. You
					always did say I didn't like to get my
					hands dirty.
				</p>
				<closer>
					<signed>Yours,
					<persName>John</persName></signed>
				</closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
