<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller Letter 1942-09-07</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n="1"/>
				<opener>
					<dateline><date>Sept 7, 1942</date>
						<placeName>Fort Bragg N.C.</placeName></dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother, Dad, + Grandma--</salute></opener>
				<p>The trip down from New Cumberland was long and tiring. We were awaked at 4:30,
					had breakfast, were checked off, loaded, and finally pulled out at 7:00. We took
					all the back roads there were. I suppose troop trains are routed that way to
					simplify transportation problems - but it took us twice as long as it would by
					the regular route. We came through York, Baltimore, + Washington, and then out
					across to Richmond. From Richmond to Raleigh we <pb n="2"/> really took the back
					way, for we saw absolutely nothing but scrub pine and small clearings with poor
					negro quarters.</p>
				<p> We arrived here at 2:30 and finally got to bed about 4:00. The camp here is
					swell. I think I shall like it. The outfit is made up of a good class of
					fellows, intelligent, clean-cut, and willing. But as far as I know, I'm the only
					college man. I'm keeping it quiet.</p>
				<p>The whole 4th Regiment is made up of specialists training groups. We are in
					telephone communications. Others include radio, cooking, office clerks, supply
					clerks, etc. </p>
				<pb n="3"/>
				<p> It is fairly certain that when we leave here, if we do at all well we'll have
					technicians rating. The other boys have evidently been sent into the regular
					artillery units, which means they'll be doing the actual firing - pulling guns-
					loading, etc. I think I was lucky.</p>
				<p>I don't know a soul here, but I'm making friends and by the time our quaranteen
					is over will be as chummy as sardines in a can.</p>
				<p>We started right in today and learned the elemental commands. <pb n="4"/> The
					first few weeks will be devoted to drill, manual of arms, etc. Later we'll get
					into the real work, with problems to solve, lines to fix + lay corrections to
					make, etc.</p>
				<p>I had my army haircut today. The barbers must think they're shearing sheep. They
					use the same methods.</p>
				<p>I shan't write again til the week-end- when I'll have more time. By then I'll
					have more to tell you too.</p>
				<closer><salute>Love,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>

			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
