<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter 1942-09-04</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div type="letter">
				<pb n='1' facs="/node/1566"/>
				
					<opener><dateline>D-8-3FARC
					Fort Bragg, N.C.</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute></opener>
				<p>This reminds me of this summer
					working on the college switch board all
					night. You see I drew another detail over
					the weekend. From noon yesterday (Saturday)
					to noon today (sunday) I'm assistant
					charge of quarters. My duties consist of
					sitting in the orderly room and answering
					the phone, making announcements over the
					speaker system, posting the guard, waking
					the boys on K.P., etc. Now it is 3:30 in
					the morning. The Corporal on duty with me
					is sleeping. I slept from 10 to 2. He sleeps
					from 2 to 6. I should have all of these
					details out of the way so that the week-end
					is clear by the 6th, but I suppose they'll
					be starting all over again then.</p>
				<pb n='2' facs="node/1567"/>
				<p>
					However if in your next letter
					you mention that you are coming down
					givingg the dates, time of arrival, etc., I can
					show that to the 1st Sgt.; and should I be
					scheduled for duty, he will relieve me. So
					don't forget to include a paragraph like
					that in your next letter.</p>
					<p>Because I'm on duty. I won't get to
					Church today, so I can't send the bullitin.
					Don't hesitate to give Tommy that
					old blue suit + the gray coat. Both are too
					small and have been for over a year. I'll
					still have the ^ dark blue pin stripe and the brownish
					tweed suit to fall back on when the war is
					over. Not to mention my summer suit.</p>
					<p>And anyway, I'll probably want something
					new then anyway, so there just isnt any
					sense in saving things if Tommy could
					use them.</p>
					<p>Yes, I did recieve a letter from
					Hub Grice. I should have asnwered it
					sooner, but I didn't. An answer is
						<pb n='3' facs="node/1568"/>
					going out in the same mail.</p>
					<p>No matter, I'm positive I never
					recieved any candy -- or anything -- from
					Aunt Virginia. I checked through my diary
					to make sure, for I enter those things there, but
					there is no mention of it. I don't think I
					gave her my change of address -- so it is quite
					possiblr that it got lost somewhere if she
					did send anything.</p>
					<p>The box of cookies have not arrived,
					but your Thursday letter has. I presume
					they will be along tomorrow. (i.e today, for
					it is now early morning.)</p>
					<p>You guessed wrong on the note
					you enclosed. It was from Art 
					Calvin -- announcing the birth of a
					baby girl -- Helen La Veine. You know
					his wife's home was Statin Island.</p>
					<p>I had a letter from Tommy +
					Agnes this week. Also one from Allen + Mary
						<pb n='4'  facs="node/2055"/>
					the latter sent me a dollar to buy candy, they
					said. But I shall use it for a meal. I also
					had a note from Herm Bower and one from
					Jane Cotteryahn. Jane is working as graduate
					assistant in the Dean of Women's Office at Pitt.
					She teaches one course and is taking work towards
					her Master's in Counseling. She and Tommy
					have broken off.</p>
					<p>I have been trying all week to get
					a Traveler's Check cashed. But the system
					around here is against me. I have to get an
					officer to cash it for me. Even a Travelers
					Check which they advertize is good anywhere.
					Register, a complaint with Mr. Green for me
					will you Dad? It seems they simply don't
					trust soldiers around here -- even with a
					thing as fool proof as a Travelers check.
					I finally gave it to the Chaplain, and I'll
					have to wait til Monday to get the money.</p>
					<p>I finally got my army driver's
					license. I am now qualified on army
						<pb n='5' facs="node/2054"/>
					army truck. I suppose now I'll be drawing
					truck divers detail. Anyway it will be
					better to drive the cool truck than to shovel
					the coal!</p>
					<p>I haven't seen Paul Johnson for 3
					weeks. I wonder if he has been shipped?
					Have you heard anything? George Purcell
					was shipped to Macon, Ga. last week. I
					haven't seen Hackenburg since I've been here, but
					I heard he was in a 6 week cycle and most
					of those boys left this week -- so I suppose he is
					gone too. Meehan has been classified in
					limited service and will be transferred. It
					seems he gets motion sickness. Brownell
					and I will probably remain here for another
					10 weeks.</p>
					<p>I am writing with a borrowed
					pen. Today mine got dropped by a fellow
					who was using it to sign a pass here
						<pb n='6' facs="node/2056"/>
					in the orderly room, The point broke. In
					a few days -- perhaps the beginning of next
					week, I shall send another box home. The
					pen will be in it. Have a new point put in
					it and keep it there. I'll buy a new one
					here, since I need it immediately and
					it would take too long to send one to me.</p>
					<p>I shall also send more letters for
					you to store away for me. My diary is almost
					filled, and I'll send that too. You may
					read it if you went too and then store it
					away for me. It is nice to have, and if I
					ever decide to write a book, it will be good
					backgeound material.</p>
					<closer>Yours,
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
					<postscript><p>P.S. They must have skunks in N. Car. too.
					I was just out to get one of the guards
					up -- and one of the little animals with a white
					tail ran in front of me not 10 ft. away.
					J.</p></postscript>

			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
