<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Zeller letter DATE</title>
            <author>John Zeller</author>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
               <resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
               <resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
            <authority>Bucknell University</authority>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
            </address>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>FORT BRAGG. N. C.
					D - 8 - 3 FARC
					Dec 6, 1942</dateline>
               <salute>Dear Mother &amp; Dad --</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
					Well, I got through the third week without
					disaster, but the next week will tell. I have
					five final exams this Thursday -- one right after
					another. So I may not get a chance to write
					on Wednesday. However I'll write as soon as I
					can -- probably Thursday night or Friday
				</p>
            <p>
					If I should be lucky enough to
					be on the shipping list for next Sunday -- I shall
					telegraph you on Saturday. Then I'd like you
					to phone me Saturday night about 10 o' clock.
					But don't phone unless I telegraph. And if
					you do phone just and for Pvt. John Zeller
					person to person, Battery D, 8th Battation, Replacement
					Center, Fort Bragg, N.C. Better place the call
					early too, for it may take a little while to get it through.
				</p>
            <p>
					If I don't ship next Sunday, and don't
					get home either, then call me the following
					Saturday.
				</p>
            <pb n="2"/>
            <p>
					I've been receiving Xmas Cards from
					quite a few of the Masons. I had one from John
					Voris in Harrisburg and a very nice letter
					from Sam Wolfe. Also had a card from the
					church.
				</p>
            <p>
					Aunt Stell sent me a box of chocolate
					covered mints. I guess she figures it's easier to
					send candy them to write. Needless to say the
					candy didn't last long.
				</p>
            <p>
					Brownell leaves for Ft. Sill tonight.
					He'll get there Wednesday or Thursday.
					I guess Paul Johnson is still waiting
					start school. He made the mistake of asking
					instead of th Field Artillery.
					to get into the Adjutant General's Office
				</p>
            <p>
					instead of th Field Artillery.
					I'm enclosing the Xmas club checks
					Please deposit them to my account.
					The underwear has not yet arrived.
					I'll let you know how it fits in
					my next letter.
				</p>
            <p>
					Last night I went to see a U.S.O.
					camp show at the "Center" Theater. They put on
				<pb n="3"/>
					"You Can't Take It With You". I had seen the
					Bucks County Playhouse do the same play in
					Shile, when I was down this summer -- and
					imagine my surprise and delight when most
					of the cast was the same. All of the women were
					the same and one of the men. The starring role
					was played by the composer Jack Norwood
					who wrote “Shine on Harvest Moon and “Take
					Me Out to the Ball Game."
				</p>
            <p>
					Some of the fellows evidently had never
					seen a legitimate theather production before,
					for they got up and left at the end of the 1st
					act. Guess they thought it was all over -- as
					in the movies.
				</p>
            <p>
					I want to go to the movies this
					afternoon and then study and go to the
					band concert tonight.
				</p>
            <p>
					Last night we finally heard on
					the radio the full story of Pearl Harbor
				<pb n="4"/>
					No wonder it has taken as long to get rolling.
					We seem to have made a remarkable recovery.
					I'm glad thd Selective Service has finally been
					made a real Selective Service. Now this foolish
					volunteering the day before the draft would take
					effect will stop.</p>
            <closer>Guess that all the news --
					<salute>Yours,</salute>
               <signed>John</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
