<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter January 30, 1943</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				
					<opener><dateline>OCC #56
					Ft. Sill, Okla.
					Jan 30,1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute></opener>
					<p>I had a "coming out" party this afternoon held over at
					the dental clinc. Yes I had a tooth pulled- my 1st molar on
					the upper left side. Doc Nesbit filled it and refilled it, until
					it was half filling anyhow. So I decided to have it pulled and
					get it over with -- knowing the army dentist would only pull it
					anyway. I’t been bothering me for some time with dull ache
					every once in a while -- and beginning this week it gave me a sharp
					pain everytime I chewed on it. Anyway its gone now.</p>
					<p>They used novocaine -- so there was no pain. The whole left
					side of my face is still numb. The tooth itself looked huge. And
					the vacancy feels big enough to drop a two story house in it.
					Before long I suppose the shot will wear off and I'll be in agony
					for awhile. Just so it's okay by tomorrow -- for we have the hardest
					week ahead.</p>
					<p>This past week wasnt any too easy. We had about 4 tests and
					3 service practices. So far I've had all 5's. I hope I can keep it
					up.</p>
					<p>Yesterday morning we took complete charge of a battery. I
					held every job there is at one time or another during the morning.
					I was Battery Commander, Executive, Gunner, Recorder, Fuse Setter,
					and just about everything else. It was a lot of fun -- and very good
				<pb n='2'/>
					experience.</p>
					<p>Yesterday afternoon we witnessed a demonstration in
					Infantry and Artillery on the Defense. It was very good -- equal
					at least to anything I've seen the movies do. Some 3,500 of
					us sat on the side of a mountain and watched the battle in the
					valley and plain below.</p>
					<p>When we first went out there I would have sworn there
					were no men out in the valley, but suddenly 500 men just
					jumped up out of nowhere and conducted a battle. How men
					can live and fight in an area as completely covered by artillery
					and machine gun fire as that was I don't know. But they
					are doing it today in Persia, China, and Africa.</p>
					<p>I saw Brownell at a distance at the demonstration -- but
					I didn't get a chance to talk to him. I guess he's still getting along
					allright. He should finish two weeks before I do.</p>
					<p>There's not much else new. I had a letter from Cousin Emma
					this week. She tells me that her church is being redecortated. About
					time, don't you think? Wonder if she is having it done?
					Last night Winn (a boy in the next hut) and I went over
					to the main post to the movies. The show wasn't particularly
					good, but the theater is wonderful. Just as nice as the Campus.
					It's supposed to be the nicest camp that in the U.S. It was
					well worth the walk just to sit in those plush seats.</p>
					<closer><salute>Love,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
