<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter January 6, 1943</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<p>
					FORT BRAGG. N. C.
					OCC #56
					St. Sill Okla.
					Jan 6, 1942
				</p>
				<p>
					Dear Mother + Dad
					It&apos;s 10:00 o&apos;clock and I&apos;ve just finished
					studging. I&apos;ll try to dash off a letter before lights
					out at 10:30.
					For some strange reason we had no classes
					Monday morning -- and so I was able to get
					to the part office for the watch. It&apos;s just what I
					hoped it would be. All the fellows are properly
					envious. It&apos;s keeping perfect time, and I find
					myself admiring it constantly. Thank you so
					much.
				</p>
				<p>
					Mine certainly was a Xmas worth waiting
					for. I have so much food I don&apos;t know where to
					store it all and I can&apos;t eat it all -- neither can
					the fellows. In addition to your fine box of food,
					for which I also thank you, I have the Groover&apos;s
					box, a 5 lb box of candy from Aunt Nelle, a box
					of hard candies from Mrs T., + lb or 2 lb box from
					the peope in the Registrar&apos;s Office on the hill. The fellows
				</p>
				<pb n='2'/>
				<p>
					say they have never seen so much food in their lives
					If you see any of those who sent me things, tell
					them how much I appreciated it. I’m writing
					of course, too.
					klaks for the iron -- it was just the type
					I wanted. Unfortunately, I discovered, I can&apos;t
					use it here because of strain on the electric
					system -- but I can use it later at some other
					camp so it&apos;s not wasted.
				</p>
				<p>
					Handkies, of course, always come in
					handy.
					I&apos;ve received another huge lunch of Xmas
					greetings forwarded from Bragg. Time doesn&apos;t permit
					my listing all of the senders. When I send the box
					home (after I empty your tins), you can look through
					then.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please send Grandma&apos;s money by money
					order. I don&apos;t get paid until Jan 30th (2 months
					pay then) and I&apos;ve had a lot of expense. ($ 10.95 foot
					locker -- suitcase -- a few books + supplies -- etc.
					Also send my electric razor if you haven&apos;t sold
					it.
					I guess I got through Motors O.K? I got
					all 5&apos;s anyway. How I don&apos;t know. We had
					our 1st Material test today. I got an 5. Also saw
				</p>
				<pb n='3'/>
				<p>
					the latest F.A. gun today It&apos;s a honey. It&apos;s still a
					military secret -- but it looks plenty powerful.
					Received papers. Thanks.
					What is D. Griffith&apos;s address, or her husbands?
					I&apos;d like to look them up if I have a chance.
				</p>
				<p>
					Young (my roommate) is from about 100
					miles upstate from Sill. He is 28, married, and
					expecting to pass out cigars an day now. Zavodnik
					is 24. We plan to take picture this Sunday. When
					we do + get them developed -- I&apos;ll send them on to you.
					Lawton is 4 miles from Sill. Nice homes.
					Reminds me of Ambry. Wide streets and all.
				</p>
				<p>
					Have not received Readers Digest. Will
					write + thank Mr. T. when I do. Did receive
					Showalter&apos;s card along with many others.
					My schedule is really getting tough. Up at
					6:00. Clean up. Compulsary breakfast. Drill 8-9.
					Classes 9-1 Lunch 1:15, classes 2-6, Supper
					6:30. Compulsary study 7:15 to 10:00. Lights
					out 10:30. It takes all of my time just to do the
					things I have to do. No time to relax or read things
					I want to.
				</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
				<p>
					I&apos;ll close now til Sunday.
					thanks again for
					everything.
					have to the best parents in the world -
					John
				</p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
