<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter January 13, 1943 (a)</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				
					<opener><dateline>Jan 13,1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute></opener>
					<p>I shall try to write a hurried note tonight. The
					assignments are a bit lighter than usual, so I have
					about an hour to myself before lights out. However I
					have a pair of does to ship too.</p>
					<p>Which reminds me that I should tell you I've
					accumulated, 2 demerits so for this week -- both in
					my capacity as hut orderly. I got one because the place
					was dirty. The Lt. ran his finger over it and got his
					glove dirty -- it looked all right to me. The other demerit
					came today because a small piece of paper stuck to the
					bottom of the track can when emptied it, and so remained
					there for inspection. However, 2 isn't bad. As long as
					I don't get 5 per week I can't kick. Everyone in our section has
					at least 1. I think the officers try to even them out.</p>
					<p>Now to answer your letters. Yes, I got a card
					from Helen, George, + Nancy, Low Kunkle -- along with
					about a million others. I suggest you check through the
					package when I send it home. You'll find plenty there.
					I think I'll try to send the package off this weekend if
				<pb n='2'/>
					I can get to the P.O.</p>
					<p>I'm sure I saw Mexican or Indian
					bracelets in the shops in town. Next time I get
					in -- probably not for a week or so -- I'll get one
					for you.</p>
					<p>Roommates continue to be good company.
					Guess I'm more capable of getting along with
					other people than you thought. Roscoe is about
					2 blocks away. But time is so limited, I never
					see him. I only see those in my own section.</p>
					<p>Glad to hear about Helen Shaffer. Wonder
					what Fred will do without her in the office.</p>
					<p>Received G'-ma's money order Ok
					but haven't had a chance to cash it. But I
					really don't need it just yet anyhow, because
					I cashed a Traveler's Cheque over at the Main
					Post Bank.</p>
					<p>Electrie razor arrived too. But I discovered
					I don't have a plug to screw it in. I'll have to postpone
					using it until I can get into town to buy one
					at the 5 + 10.</p>
					<p>So you got a 95 in Hursing class.
					Mathe. See, I told you it wouldn't be any
					trouble.</p>
				<pb n='3'/>
					<p>I you see Janet Bold, Mrs. Bond, or anyone
					else who might know (maybe Betty Herrold could
					find out) would you please get Margie Clayton's
					address for me. I had a note from her without a
					return address.</p>
					<p>I've had letters from lots of my friends this week.
					Dan, Janet, Jane C., Ken, Dave, and Ted all
					wrote. All my mail seems to come in spurts. Not
					much new from any of them. Don wants the war
					to get over quickly so he can go home &amp; marry
					Janet. Jane likes her job at Pitt very much
					and offers to show me the town if I get shipped
					to Pittsburg. (Wonder if that's a hint?) Ken is
					working hard. He had only 4 days home at Xmas -- spent
					the rest at a Baptist conference in Mich. Dan likes
					his new post, he says, and as usual is sarcastic
					about field artillery. Ted expects a furlough soon and
					a promotion too. I guess that convers that.</p>
					<p>I have a picture folder of this area to send
					you as soon as I get to the P.O. to buy stamps.
					I'm going to send one to Grandma, too.</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
					<p>Gunnery so far hasn't been too bad -- but
					I would be completely and hopelessly lost if I
					had it had that prep course at Bragg.</p>
					<p>Oh yes -- almost forget the most important
					thing. I went to the hospital as ordered yesterday.
					They just wanted to check about my hayfever.
					They ask a few questions and wrote up a history on
					the sheet. The Dr. told me I would probably have
					to sign a waiver. All of which means that
					if I die of hayfever the government will be
					relieved of responsibility -- you probably wouldnt
					be able to collect my insurance in that case either.
					Outside of that -- it wasn't as serious as I
					anticipated.</p>
					<p>Dad, will you do me a favor. Check with
					Uncle Tom &amp; get train schedules, fare, etc for me
					from Oklahoma City to Harrisburg. When I do
					finish here I'll want to leave as soon as I can,
					and since I'll be traveling overnight + for a
					long distance I'll want to make reservations far
					enough in advance.</p>
					<p>I'm going to check at this end to see how much
					it would cost to fly in.</p>
					<closer><salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
