<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/zeller/refs/heads/main/out/zeller.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LEAF-VRE/code_snippets/refs/heads/main/CSS/leaf.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter January 26, 1943</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>FORT BRAGG, N.C.
					OCC #56
					Ft. Sill, Okla.
					Jan. 26, 1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>
					Needless to say, I'm very much tickled with your
					surprise. I was more than a little disappointed when you
					didn't have it done for Christmas. I thought perhaps you werent
					going to do it at all. But I decided I was through coaxing. And
					you finally had the pictures taken! I certainly am proud.
					Winskaitis -- the new boy in the hut -- told me that you two
					look just like parents should look. I told him you were just
					like parents should be, too.</p>
					<p>I think your picture Dad, makes you look younger. The
					fellows think I look like you more than Mother.
				</p>
				<p>
					Your picture, Mother, makes your jaw a bit more square
					than it actually is. It certainly pictures the fine lady that you
					are. And it shows off your white hair to good advantage.
					Both are good likenesses.</p>
					<p>Grandma's picture is good too -- but it lacks the "grand old lady"
					appearance she can put on when she gets all dressed up. She's a
					good looking old lady just the same though.</p>
					<p>I'm certainly tickled that you had them made. I don't
					know of anything you could have done that would please ne
					more.</p>
					<p>I shall take care of my transportation from this end 
					then. I don't know where to find the railway transportation advisor
				<pb n='2'/>
					here -- and wouldn't have time to look him up if I did. But
					I guess some arrangement can be worked out. I've written
					to the air lines to see what kind of service I can get from Okla.
					City + just how much it will cost. If I'm going to fly I'll
					have to make an early reservation.</p>
					<p>Young got word just today (seems the baby was late)
					and its a girl. Both mother + babe are doing nicely. It weighed
					9 lbs. It would be nice if I could give it something. Suppose
					you send me a baby cup or spoon and I'll have him send it
					on home. I don't know his wife's address.</p>
					<p>He's very much relieved, of course, but a bit disappinted
					too. He wanted a boy. Just the same his plenty tickled about it.
					I was out on the range again today and fired another
					problem. It was cold again. This wind certainly plays
					hob with the weather.</p>
				<p>
					When I come home I think I'll spend a day or so in Philly.
					Uniforms out here are hard to get -- and fits are particularly bad.
					If I could go to Phila., I could get what I need to fit me.
					Perhaps you + Dad could go with me -- or if I fly in, could
					you meet me there. We'll have to see how things work out.</p>
					<p>Not much new. Charles again for the pictures
					and for the candy, too.</p>
					<closer><salute>Your son,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
