<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/zeller/refs/heads/main/out/zeller.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/zeller/refs/heads/main/zeller.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter February 7, 1943</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n="1"/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>FORT BRAGG, N.C. OCC #56 F.t. Sill, Okla. Feb 7, 1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad</salute></opener>
				<p>Well, what we've always feared has finally happened. Alice tells me that Margaret
					Ocksenreiter lost her job. Now you'll have that to worry about, Dad. She
					certainly has no business living in our apartment on her salary! It's just one
					thing after another, isn't it.</p>
				<p>I'm glad you liked the bracelet, Mother. I didn't know whether you wanted that
					kind or one of the more fancy ones.</p>
				<p>I'm told the R.R. transportation adviser comes around a few weeks before we
					graduate and helps plan our travel route. I have written about air reservations,
					but haven't as yet received an answer. I hope I can get a sent or a plane -- it
					would make it much nicer.</p>
				<p>Well, I got my 1st U this week. I was called on to fire a problem in service
					practice and couldn't find the taget. I hope I won't be set back because of it.
					The Lt. said I shouldn't worry about it -- that you weren't a good man until you
					got at least 1. U. If I don't get more than one, I won't kick. </p>
				<pb n="2"/>
				<p> I really don't have much to write about today. We've just been doing the same
					old things. We had an interesting demonstration yesterday afternoon. I told
					Alice about it in her letter -- you can read it there.</p>
				<p>Last evening Ken Wright (Jackson, Mich boy) and I started for town, and after
					walking all over the post trying to find transportation, finally walked about ¾
					of the way into town, before getting a taxi. The moves were all over-crowded, so
					we had a meal and then waited in line again for a taxi to come back to the post.
					I'll be so glad to get somewhere where I won't have to stand in line for
					everything, that I won't know what to do.</p>
				<p>You'll have to serve meals off tin plates and cafeteria style to make me feel at
					home when I come home.</p>
				<p>I'm spending the day reading and writing letters again. Sunday's seem to go that
					way out here. And we just seem to live from Sunday to Sunday.</p>
				<p>I had a letter from Jean Dryer this week. She's had a raise and is worried about
					meeting her 1st income tax payment. Also heard from Hal and Emmie.</p>  
				<closer>
					Guess that's all,
					<salute>Love,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
