<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter DATE</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>Officer Canidate Class #56
					Fort Sll, Okla.
					Jan 3,1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute></opener>
					<p>Happy New Year - even if a bit late. I'm afraid
					this letter will just ramble on and on without much
					order. First of all, before I forget it, I bought 2 set.
					of crossed canon for you Mother. When I send the box
					home (sometime within the next two weeks), you'll find
					them in the envelope with my Center School Certificate.
					notice of being made a Corporal, Corporals stripes, and
					O.C.S. insignia. Hope you can use them. Now
					to answer your letters.</p>
					<p>1st. your letter of Dec. 16 forwarded from
					Bragg. Thanks for the money order. I got it cashed
					without any trouble at all and it came in handy. Particularly
					since I won't be paid for Dec. until the end of Jan. because
					of moving. I've written to Aunt Stella.</p>
					<p>I was so sorry to hear about Mrs. Bird and
					Linda Fairchild. I wrote a note to the Steins + Mrs.
					Brown -- and to Aunt Virginia.
				</p>
				<pb n='2'/>
				<p>
					You haven't told me what my gifts to others for
					Xmas cost. Tell me and I'll send you a check. Now
					do it! I'll be mad if you don't.
					Incidentally -- don't waste 10 ¢ on special delivery.
					The army just doesn't have that service. If you want
					to send letters air mail a 6 ¢ stamp will do it. Also
					I want to remind you again not to send insured
					or registered mail unless the contents absolutely
					require it. We just don't get the chance to get to the P.O.
					to pick them up.</p>
					<p>I got notice yesterday that there is a registered
					package there for me. But I can't get it. The P.O.
					isn't open when I'm free. I'm just going to have to
					skip noon chow tomorrow if I want it before next
					Saturday. The same is true of insured mail. Tell
					folks not to insure mail to soldiers. I havent received
					any Xmas packages yet -- but I should get them soon.</p>
					<p>I doubt if I shall be able to phone you from
					here. But I might be able to some day if I can get near
					a phone. If you ever went to call me however -- call
					person to person. Officer Conidate Class #56, Ft. Sill.
					They'll let me know, and I'll call back.</p>
					<p>You folks certainly have been gadding around.
				<pb n='3'/>
					I envy you all the good meals you must be
					having.</p>
					<p>I'm glad you finally got the electric door bell. I
					I know how you wanted it.</p>
					<p>Don't worry about opening the card from Ann
					Hamilton. I don't mind in the least.</p>
					<p>I'm inclosing the Pa. drivers license form.
					Incidentally, I like your new stationery, Mother.
					I signed up for $ 25 bond a mo. after Jan 1st. I'm
					having them sent home. You know what to do with them
					Dad.</p>
					<p>I got the letter from Boris Raynes. He was one
					of my good friends at Penn., and was drafted last
					spring. It seems I'm just following him around --
					for he was at Bragg too. He's here now waiting
					for overseas duty. I went over to see him New Years
					day and we went into Lawton to a show together
					last night. He was certainly surprised to see me.</p>
					<p>I got a surprise too the other day. While in
					the tailor shop chatting with Roscoe Brownell, I
					happened to look around and there standing next to me
				<pb n='4'/>
					was a boy from Shippensburg S. T. I had roomed
					with at Eagles Mere 2 years ago. It's a small world
					isn't it. He's in O.C.S. too.</p>
					<p>Our hut has a gas stove that keeps the place
					fairly wam dispite all of the windows and the cement
					floor. But we have to turn it off at night -- so its
					plenty cold in the morning.</p>
					<p>We eat in a huge mess hall cafeteria style
					on the stamped metal trays you see pictures off. The
					food here can't bad, if we just had time to eat it.
					They serve soups, thank goodness, so we get really
					warmed on cold days. We never had soup at Bragg.</p>
					<p>Say "hello" to everyone for me. I appreciated
					so much the card from evenone -- the Shieters,
					Beards, Pearl, Deafy Comstock, Maude, and
					everyone.</p>
					<p>Now to tell you a bit of what I have been
					doing. We arise at 6:00 and police up. There are
					demerits for wrinkles in the bed or dust on shoes or a
					dirty hut. We eat at 7:15. At 9:00 we start classes.
					Lunch at 1:00. Classes again from 2:00 til 6:00. From
					7:20 to 10:30 we have to study in our huts. If we
				<pb n='5'/>
					leave for any reason we have to mark it on a
					sign over the bed.</p>
					<p>Motors wasn't as bad as I expected, but
					it was embarrassing for a greenhorn to have to
					take a truck apart +put it back together again. I
					had to ask how to do everything I did. But I learned
					a lot.</p>
					<p>We drove some too -- up + down steep hills and
					over roads our Olds would never have made. Tomorrow
					we get one final exam and then go on into the
					course on Material.</p>
					<p>With the holidays, I've been fortunate in
					being able to get into Lawton. I had an excellent
					meal there New Year's day. It's not a bad town at
					all. Much better than Fayettesville. But of course Okla.
					is dry -- they sell only 3.2 beer. I've seen quite a few
					Indians on the street and a few cowboys. Stores
					feature indian trinkets -- combat boots + saddles. It
					is the county seal of Comanche County. That sounds like
					real wild west, doesn't it.</p>
				<pb n='6'/>
				<p>
					Glad Xmas business was so good, Dad. How much
					merchandise do you have left?
					I guess that's all the news, I want to go
					over to the old post (very picturesque) to get a foot
					locker this afternoon, so I'll close now.</p>
					<closer><salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
					<postscript><p>P.S. Dad, if you didn’t sell my electric razor,
					please send it on to me. I could use it here and
					save the 2 block trip to the latrine on cold mornings.</p></postscript>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
