<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/zeller/refs/heads/main/out/zeller.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/zeller/refs/heads/main/zeller.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">	
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter February 3, 1943</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				
					<opener>
						<dateline>FORT BRAGG. N. C.
					OCC #56
					F.t. Sill Okla.
					Feb 3,1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute></opener>
					<p>8:00 A.M. Thanks very much for the box of candy. It arrived
					last night. The boys join me in thanking you. Next time, tho,
					don't buy the expensive kind. Just send some of their peanut
					buttle, peanut clusters, kisses, chocolate sticks, or something
					like that.</p>
					<p>I'm glad you had such a good time in Williamsport,
					Dad. Wish I could have gone up this year. As far as overseas
					duty is concerned, I don't want to have to make the choice
					myself. If they send me over, why of course I'll go -- and
					if they assign me to duty here, I'll do that too. This army
					business wasn't my idea and I'm willing to do whatever
					they want me to -- but I'm not going to try to control the
					situation to suit myself. I'll take what's offered me and let it
					go at that.</p>
					<p>Glad you had such a good time at the Class Supper
					Mother. I didn't ever really meet Mrs. Shimer, but I always
					thought her to be very nice too.</p>
					<p>I hope you've received the bracelet this time, and
					that it was satisfactory.</p>
				<pb n='2'/>
				<p>
					Sid Appelbaum still has some of my law school
					difests doesn't he. Let me know when he returns them.
					Also let me know if you will received my government
					insurance policy and if my government bond for Jan.
					has arrived yet.</p>
					<p>I had a very amusing letter from Isabelle this week.
					I enjoy her letters so much. It's just like having her pop
					in for a moment as she used to.</p>
					<p>My tooth is much better. Once it was out, I had
					no more trouble. Now I think I'll have Doc Nesbit Jr.
					pull another one when I come home. My gums are healing
					nicely too.</p>
					<p>I forget about Aunt Stella's birthday -- I'll have
					to apologize when I write to Grandma this week-end.</p>
					<p>Did Janet Bold graduate at Jan. commencement.
					Last I heard she was planning to.</p>
					<p>I've written this much of this letter before class
					It rained yesterday (second time since I've been here) and
					the field was more than muddy -- just plain goo. Hence we
					had no drill this morning. That gives me an extra half hour
					this morning to myself. It's just about time for class, so
					I'll close for now and finish this evening.
				</p>
				<pb n='3'/>
				<p>
					<time>8.00 P.M. --</time>
					Your box of candy from Williamsport
					arrived today, Dad. thanks very much.
					So far I haven't made any serious errors
					this week. I always seem to make at least one
					silly little "careless" mistake to keep me from
					getting a perfect paper. However, I'm satisfied
					with 5's.</p>
					<p>I fired again this morning. I was called
					on to fire before I had a chance to figure the correct
					commands. So I just stood up and rattled off
					a string of guesses. As it turned out I couldn't have
					done better, for I registered on the tanget on my 1st
					shot. Pure luck!</p>
					<p>It rained yesterday -- and today I learned
					about Ft. Sill mud. I've never seen roads like
					the ones we used to go out to the range. We were stuck
					at least 3 times -- and other trucks were more
					hopelessly mired all along the way.
				</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
				<p>
					Dont plan anything for me in the morning when I
					come home. I'm going to sleep late every morning, I'm
					getting so tired of getting up before sun-up! Sunday is
					really a big relief -- and even then it's hard to sleep after
					seven.</p>
					<p>It's time to start studying again for I want to
					have time for a shower tonight before 10:30. So
					I'll close.</p>
					<closer><salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
