<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter January 20, 1943</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>FORT BRAGG, N. C.
					OCC #56
					Ft. Sill, Okla.
					Jan 20, 1942</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>					
					I’ve finished my homework at 9:30 tonightt for some
					strange reason -- so I'm going to spend the hour before lights
					out in writing this note and making a 10-minute trip to the PX.</p>
					<p>I've just returned from the PX -- fast trip, wasn't it?
					I wish you could see the mob there. OCS men are not allowed to
					go after 7:20 nor before 9:30 -- so it's really mobbed from 9:30
					to 10:00 (closing time). I could hardly get in. And I had to push + shove
					+ fight my way to the candy counter. Supplies as low. We too are
					rationed. Candy bars are doled out three to a person. Last week
					it was five -- but things are tightening up.
				</p>
				<p>
					Ice cream is getting more scare too - so the PX is
					tiyng to puch sherbet + ice. That's all they had tonight. I imagine
					your folks are really feeling the pinch.</p>
					<p>Now to answer your letter of Jan 15th. Grits, Mother
					are like oatmeal or much. Hominy is corn, evidently soaked
					like rice or tapioca before cooking, for the kernals are big and
					white. I don't care for either.</p>
					<p>Why don't you go visit, Isabelle or Aunt Va.,
					Mother. It's the only chance you'll have -- for once Grandma
					gets back + with gas rationing and all -- you'll not get away
				<pb n='2'/>
					again until fall. And I'm sure Dad won't mind
					eating out for a few days.</p>
					<p>You don't need to think only Pa. is cold. A
					north wind blew in here Sunday night and Monday and
					brought below zero temperatures. Th infirmary was
					damned with frozen ears, noses, feet, + fingers. I was
					out in it almost all my Monday and my right hand,
					was front bitten. It's been numb ever since.</p>
					<p>The wind is so biting that it really gets cold.
					Fortunately I do have enough convers -- so that its warm
					in bed, any way. The hat itself is some protection from the
					wind -- but it's just as cold as outside.</p>
					<p>To top it all off the gas main broke tonight and
					we had no heat at all until almost 9:00.</p>
					<p>We have another new roommate - dropped back
					from a class one week ahead of us. He had flu + was in the
					hospital 4 days. His name is Winskaitis + he's from
					Chicago. Lithwanian by nationality. Seems like a nice
					chap. He's younger than I -- and married.</p>
				<p>
					I finally mailed the box last night. You should
					receive it about the same time as this letter. It includes the
					tin cas you sent the food in -- and some of Aunt Edna's too.
					My letters are in the cans. Also my diary -- rather poorly bound --
					but it least it will hold together until I find a better
					binder.</p>
					<p>My notice of promotion to Cpl + my Center School
					diploma are in the brown envelope along with my stripes
					OCS insignia, + your little crossed cannon, Mother. The Xmas
					menu and a few other things are also inclosed. You can
				<pb n='3'/>
					put the Reader's Digest in my bookcase! They make such
					good reference material, I like to keep them.</p>
					<p>I suggest you look through the mail + see who all
					sent Xmas cards. Then when you see the folks who remembered
					me you can tell them how much I appreciated it.</p>
					<p>I hope to get into town this Saturday. Last weekend
					was too crowded, I didn't make it. If I do, I shall look for
					trinkets.</p>
				<p>
					I haven't been getting the Bucknellian from the CA
					regularly -- so if you can without too much trouble, please
					send it along with the Journal + Sat. News. Thank you.
					We were out on the range Monday to fire our 1st
					gunnery problems in the freezing cold. I was one of the 1st
					to fire and did all right up until the very end when I
					got excited and moved the gun the wrong direction. I
					haven't received my grade yet -- but I have hopes of an 5.
					We were out again today -- not as cold this time -- and
					the rest of the class fired.</p>
					<p>Friday we fire again on a different type
					problem. I guess from now on we'll be spending
					about half our time out of doors. I hope it gets warm.</p>
				<pb n='4'/>
					<p>I had a letter from Dave again. He wants to know
					what OCS is like, + how tough the entrance exam was.
					So I wrote + gave him the lowdown.</p>
					<p>I also had a letter from Dick Nutt. He + Dottie
					all sailing happily along. He's decided to be a Methodist,
					and is to be ordained -- or whatever the Methodist's do -- within
					the next month</p>
					<p>It's time for light out now so I'll close.</p>
					<closer><salute>Yours,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
