<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter January 13, 1943 (b)</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				<opener>
					<dateline>FORT BRAGG, N. C.
					OCC #56
					Ft. Sill.
					Jan 13,1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad</salute>
				</opener>
				<p>
					We got paid sooner than expected -- so I'm in the
					money again -- and with January payday just 15 days
					away -- I have much more then I need just now. Consequently I'm
					Sending home the inclosed money order for $45. Place deposit it
					to my checking account.</p>
					<p>Yes I wrote to Emma H. + thanked her for her
					Xmas present -- also to most everyone except a few
					hundred who sent Xmas cards.</p>
					<p>For the answer to your question on clymate
					consult my this week's letter to Alice. She asked much
					the same question. However it is much dryer than N.C. --
					so not as disagreeable and damp. Not yet, anyway.</p>
				<p>
					Glad Bob Rishel is in OCS too. What
					branch of the service and where?
					The peaniut butter cookies didn't carry too
					well. The chocolate ones were delicious however. I ate
					the crumbs of the others and enjoyed them too.
				</p>
				<pb n='2'/>
				<p>
					Well the 1st week of gunnery is over. We've had
					two tests. I had a perfect paper in one and only
					only one small mistake in the other. Monday I'll get my
					1st chance to show what I have learned in a practical way,
					for we go out on the range to fire our 1st problems.
					We fire three times next week -- so I'll really have to
					concentrate. It's a lot different from paper firing, for
					on the range we have to carry all the figures in our head
					and make all our additions &amp; subtractions mentally. Hope
					I make out all right.
				</p>
				<p>
					This afternoon - Saturday - we were out firing
					anti-ancraft machine guns at balloons. It was fun, but
					I didn't do too well. Guess it takes practice. We also fired
					the revolver, carbine, and Tommy gun. I did best with
					the Tommy gun -- 7 out of 8. With the small arms we
					did combat firing (not aiming) jut quickly pointing
					in the direction of fire &amp; pulling the trigger. I did
					all right.
				</p>
				<p>
					Young's wife is due to have a baby this week-end.
					He's all on edge. Doesn't know whether he's going to be
					a father or a mother, he says!</p>
					<p>I hope to get into town tomorrow afternoon to
					mail the package and to look for an Indian bracelet.
					for you, Mother. Don't know whether I will or not.
					I guess that's all the news.</p>
					<closer><salute>Love,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed></closer>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
