<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0" 
href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"? 
        href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"
href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BucknellDSC/shared_code/refs/heads/main/leaf.css"	
        ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Zeller letter January 10, 1943</title>
				<author>John Zeller</author>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Susan Falciani Maldonado</persName>
					<resp>University Archivist and Director of Special Collections</resp>
				</respStmt>
				<respStmt>
					<persName>Diane Jakacki</persName>
					<resp>Digital Scholarship Coordinator</resp>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<distributor>Special Collections/University Archives, Bertrand Library</distributor>
				<authority>Bucknell University</authority>
				<address>
					<addrLine>Lewisburg</addrLine>
					<addrLine>Pennsylvania</addrLine>
				</address>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>John F. Zeller Papers</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<pb n='1'/>
				
					<opener>
						<dateline>Officer Canidate Class #56
					Ft. Sill, Okla.
					Jan 10,1943</dateline>
					<salute>Dear Mother + Dad --</salute></opener>
					<p>Charles for the mush receipt. I'll pass it on to
					the cook -- mush ought to make a better breakfast than
					the grits &amp; hominy we've been getting.</p>
					<p>You two have certainly been doing the gadding
					lately. Guess you're just trying to make up for me --
					someone has got to keep the family socially in the 400.</p>
					<p>We got a new room mate this week. He's an old
					army man -- been in for 13 years. Frankly, we all
					think he's a big blowhouse, but I've never met anyone
					yet I couldn't get along with if I had to -- so things
					will continue to run smoothly.</p>
					<p>I got the results of all of my Motor's exams,
					and I got through it all right. I was more worried
					about that than anything else -- although Gunnery which
					we start tomorrow -- is supposed to be the hardest.
					Material wasn't at all bad. We fooled
					around with all kinds of guns. I really learned a
					lot. We had one final exam and a lecture this morning,
					Sunday, so I didn't get to check again. I've just
				<pb n='2'/>
					about given up hope of getting to services here. Even
					Sunday they pull something on us. And as for seeing
					anything of this part of the country -- well I've defintely
					decided there's no use to even think about it.</p>
					<p>The Christmas package food is beginning to
					dwindle a bit. I can actually open my footlocker
					without having things forced out. I had an awful
					time getting the lid closed for awhile.</p>
					<p>There was no mail today for some strange
					reason. Guess the mailman must be on strike. All of
					us are curious. Usually we have plenty of service in
					that department if in none other.</p>
					<p>I can't think of much else to write about -- once
					one gets into the routine there's really not much to
					tell. I'll try to write again in the middle of the week.</p>
					<closer><salute>Yours with love,</salute>
					<signed>John</signed>.</closer>
					<postscript><p>P.S. I want to tell you this. I've been ordered
					to report to the hospital Tuesday afternoon. Ouite a few
					others are to go too. I'm afraid they may have caught
					up with me on my hayfever. But I'm going to be
					really provoked if they don't let me finish here now
					that I've gone this far. We shall see what it's all
					about Tuesday.</p></postscript>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
